PAUL: Okay, so now, I felt that, many of you were stuck very specifically with respect to installation issues. So, like, even in the forum, when I looked into, like, how many of you feel that the installation part is very hard?
PAUL: Yes, please let me know.
PAUL: Because this is important with respect to installation. Because at the end of the day, if you're stuck with respect to installation, yes.
PAUL: The problem is there.
PAUL: Even I get stuck, it's not like that in one shot even I can do it sometimes. Even when I'm working with the latest versions very specifically.
PAUL: there can be some type of issues with respect to the stability and the compatibility of one package with another package. This is a very common problem that even everyone faces. It's not like that in one shot, everybody can do it. Once I start working with a particular framework, in a longer run, I know that, okay, now these are the common errors that comes.
PAUL: Tell the time if you are not working in long run.
PAUL: Just in the initial phase, it takes more time, but once you start working, okay, then…
PAUL: The idea is that it, you are much more familiar with respect to those framework-based errors. Okay.
PAUL: Alright, today, I will try to do… okay, I will just take…
PAUL: They are my way of doing the stuff and doing the installation.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with our today's agenda. So today, another framework that we'll be discussing, which is very specific with part of the data ingestion phase. Okay, unstructured. So, let me start sharing my screen.
PAUL: Let me shook.
PAUL: Okay, I think everybody is able to see my screen. Please let me know.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, unstructured, very specifically, like, I've already given you, majorly, all the stuff, okay, with respect to the installation.
PAUL: Anybody has tried the installation?
PAUL: Okay, and let me, before that, rag.md, just wait.
PAUL: Where is the file?
PAUL: Okay, so today I will do it, I will try to do that stuff.
PAUL: Alright, so, right now.
PAUL: In the previous class, very specifically with respect to frameworks, one of the frameworks, Dockling, we have gone through, okay, and the idea is that, you guys should also adopt Dockling, it's really good.
PAUL: Okay, if you are going with open source. Then another version today we'll be exploring, which is Unstructured. Unstructured has basically, the open source one, and even it has a very specific, enterprise edition, where you can create
PAUL: Like, different type of pipelines and workflows, okay, from different type of data sources. Like, they have characters.
PAUL: So today, we'll be looking into the open source version of Unstructured, and once we have done, then, let's see, like, today can… if we can do Llama parts very specifically, or next week, probably, we will start, okay? The agent is pretty much clear, like, unstructured, after that, Llama parts, and after that, vectorize.
PAUL: That very specifically, we'll be looking into. Okay, and then finally, we will start with our project part.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Now, because, unstructured notebook was already shared yesterday in the GitHub repo, so how many of you have really looked into the installation part and done the setup?
PAUL: Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: No, no, no, not every Thursday for anyone. There is no class every Thursday. Only last time it was there.
PAUL: Setup done. Alright, fine. Like, today, like, few people are telling not done, not done.
PAUL: So, let me take the risk. Okay, I will just delete everything from my site, and I will try to do it from scratch.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, just wait one minute, somebody is up the door, I think.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody just open your studio. Okay, so I will try to do the installation from scratch.
PAUL: And let me see what type of issues Okay, we get.
PAUL: Sorry to mention, but the session did impact me personally. So, Monmouth, it totally depends, like, going forward, yes, we will be having some classes.
PAUL: But yes, you need to cook that up.
PAUL: Okay, but not every Thursday. It's only when I feel that it is required, then we will do it on Thursday.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, everyone, please open your setup, okay? And right now, let me start working with environment.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just… Open up, so I think CD downloads document passes, okay? Now,
PAUL: Let me just delete whatever is there with respect to the environment.
PAUL: Okay, everybody, so right now, I'll be creating a virtual environment from scratch. Okay, and then I will be basically doing the setup.
PAUL: Okay? Everybody?
PAUL: Like, for whom you have already done, it's great. Otherwise, you can do it parallelly with me.
PAUL: So, first of all, I'm just creating a virtual environment.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: I hope my screen is visible to everyone.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, in the next step, activating the environment.
PAUL: Now, very specifically, I want to do the installation of the packages, okay? And right now, let's leave the packages of last class, okay, and let's very specifically focus on today's class, okay?
PAUL: So, here, right now, if you really look into what are the packages that I have? One is majorly with respect to AN structure that I have.
PAUL: Okay, so this UBP install, unstructured, PDF, docs, XLS, PPDX, okay, image, alright.
PAUL: So this, I can actually paste it here.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on this, I think last two are not there, okay?
PAUL: So let's do the installation, at least.
PAUL: Alright, I have done it, the installation part, with respect to unstructured, very specifically.
PAUL: Now, if something is missing, there can be issues with respect to some packages, but at least I will do the verification. Now, the next packages are, Langchen Unstructured, the Langchen Community, and the Langchen OpenEL.
PAUL: Okay, alright. These are the other packages, which is very specifically mentioned.
PAUL: So, let's do a UV pip install, land chain unstructured, to do the integration of LanChain with unstructured, then comes your LanChain Community and LanChain OpenAI.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, the other packages that I have here in the notebook, I think there is…
PAUL: Okay, ChromaDB, alright, ChromaDB is there.
PAUL: Generally, I use ChromaDB with LangChain Chroma, okay? So, I will just add that package also. Langshan hyphen Chroma.
PAUL: Alright, so now, 3 major packages, those were very specifically mentioned in the notebook. I have done the installation of those, okay? Now, coming to, as we'll be working very specifically with respect to…
PAUL: In Jupyter Notebook, okay, so let me just install the package of Jupyter, because with that, IPY kernel will be coming. Okay, so I will do a pip install…
PAUL: Jupiter?
PAUL: Alright, now this part is also done. So, step by step, all the things that I have done.
PAUL: Okay, so whatever was there mentioned very specifically in the notebook. Okay, now let me try, so first of all.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: a new kernel that I am using very specifically. Okay, so right now, based on the environment, so this is the current one.
PAUL: Now, let's try to look into the imports, if everything is working fine, or am I getting some type of errors?
PAUL: Okay, so I can see here very specifically that the installation part, and with respect to the version that I am getting right now in unstructured. Now, the next step, just checking that environment variables are getting loaded successfully. Okay, yes, it is getting loaded.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, there are a lot of partitions. Okay, so very specifically, unstructured uses this concept of partition. We'll be talking about that, but first of all, let me see that all these imports are working or not.
PAUL: Because, yes… It always happens, and some type of issues we might get. It's a common problem.
PAUL: Okay, now, others, please do have a check, because in my case, this is taking time.
PAUL: for… initially, it takes a lot of time. For the first time, once we have done the environment setup, so the initial call with respect to the
PAUL: all the necessary, I can say, imports, the indexing is done. Around 47 seconds it took for you, okay? In my case, it can be more also.
PAUL: But at least see, because if I get an error here, it means that there is really some problem with respect to unstructure. It can be a compatibility issue with respect to Python, or some other issues also.
PAUL: it's done for me in 8 seconds. Okay, it can vary, because right now, I've just created everything from scratch. Okay, so right now, in my system, it took around 1 minute.
PAUL: 6 seconds, if I'm talking.
PAUL: Now, okay, now this is one part of the section where, very specifically, all unstructured stuff that I have taken into account.
PAUL: Now, the other part of the notebook is basically with respect to langchain integration.
PAUL: So, there can be some issues there also. Now, let me quickly look into that part, that everything is working fine, because I have not done any installation other than Langchain.
PAUL: unstructured. Only one package that I have done the installation, and with respect to, I think, some community… the core Langshan package, I have not done the installation, okay? So, let me see whether it works or not.
PAUL: somewhere where I think there will be a use case with respect to…
PAUL: LandChain integration, okay? So, this is the other package that we have done it. So, let me see whether this package is getting… okay, now this import is working fine.
PAUL: Okay, other than that, any other imports are there, very specifically?
PAUL: Let me have a look.
PAUL: Alright, now, here you have,
PAUL: your, chaining part. Okay, now, these packages, do you think that we have installed in our system?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Always check.
PAUL: Because these packages, if I try to do, okay, I feel that I might get an error, but let's see.
PAUL: Okay, Lanshan Classic is not there, alright. So, one package that is missing is LanChain Classic.
PAUL: Okay, so quickly, I will just do a PYPI operation of Blanchen Classic.
PAUL: Okay, so the last release was around 17th October, let me just copy this stuff.
PAUL: Okay, and I will paste it here. You reap install engine classic. Okay, with Classic, I think letters that got added.
PAUL: Okay, fine.
PAUL: Let me just, do a kernel restart.
PAUL: A widget, please install PDFminer.6. Don't install only PDFminer.
PAUL: Okay? And actually, the command that I've given, I think that it should be up and working, okay? Now, let's see whether it works or not. Even I'm not sure whether it will work, because some packages might fail.
PAUL: Now, really, no modulum langchain underscore text splitter.
PAUL: Now, I know that this is basically the import, and we do have blanket texts better.
PAUL: Okay, now one module that is coming, but really… now this…
PAUL: time, like, even for me now, I have to debug exactly what is the issue.
PAUL: So, for example, Langshan text splitters are here, which is installed, okay? UV pip show…
PAUL: This particular package, I already have it here.
PAUL: Okay, and the version with which it is coming.
PAUL: Okay, so… Okay, let me check the import part.
PAUL: Okay, let me just…
PAUL: Check it, Lang Chen. I don't think it is Lang Chen. Okay, let me check if the input is working fine with the dot, alright.
PAUL: Now,
PAUL: the package was there, in that input, I think, very specifically, the issue was coming. Okay, and now it got solved.
PAUL: Okay, so sometimes you need to even look into. So, sometimes here, like, the idea is to… we have installed Langshan Chroma, so use it, rather than calling it from the community vector store.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, this part is done. I don't think there are any other major imports, okay? Because then comes your retrieval Q&A, and this stuff is done. So I hope for everybody, the thing that we have done, please let me know.
PAUL: Everybody has done the part with respect to installation.
PAUL: So I think there should not be, any issues, okay?
PAUL: Alright, so I think we can start.
PAUL: What did change for Classic? Classic was totally not available, so I installed Classic manually.
PAUL: What does that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Don't…
PAUL: Here, very specifically with respect to document parsing. So, again, now this is the part where you will be reading different type of documents, okay? Now, the same thing that can be done in Dockling, the idea is to explore it in unstructured. Similarly, like, now going forward, after unstructured, things where we'll be using some type of APIs, like Lama Parse is pretty much widely used.
PAUL: So the idea is to explore LlamaPars very specifically, which is basically a cloud service. We'll be taking some APIs, and based on that, we'll be doing our implementations. But right now, again, this is open source. Generally, in my data ingestion, I can say.
PAUL: Implementations, okay, so, like, unstructured always plays a crucial role, like.
PAUL: My main two libraries that I always use if I'm going ahead with open source. So, like, Docklands and Unstructured.
PAUL: So, first of all, the same things which docking can do, this also can do.
PAUL: Okay, and similarly, integration with Langchains are directly available. So… but few other things with respect to working with high-resolution stuff, okay, and for that, you need to install some packages, when we will come to that. Okay, so very specifically in your system, you need to install Poplar, but
PAUL: Now, I think we can start our main part. Okay, so… now I will just restart all the kernel, okay, and then let me start executing the first part. So, first of all, I hope the… yeah, the idea is, guys, please don't do just pip install unstructured.
PAUL: The idea is that we'll be working with different type of file formats. At any point of time, if you just do pip install unstructured, the other file format dependency packages won't get installed in your system. So, very specifically, that's why I've given this entire thing.
PAUL: Okay, so please follow that.
PAUL: Okay, and directly, like, if you look into requirement.txt, that's why today I didn't look into requirement.txt, because I know the core commands with respect to installation, I have already provided it directly in the notebook.
PAUL: Okay, R, like, that particular import was working, so very specifically, I have used it. Okay?
PAUL: Alright, now, so always remember, this is the main one that you have, so always try to do in this particular way the installation, rather than just
PAUL: Installing standalone unstructured.
PAUL: Fine. So, the next step is basically, so, the version check. So, right now, if you look into the version, I feel that I am using the latest version of Unstructured, which is released right now. Okay, so if I do a quick check, okay, now, really, working with letters versions can bring… bring…
PAUL: Some type of issues, but I… Think.
PAUL: Let's go forward, okay, release history. So, 24th November, the release was there, okay? So, pretty much new one, and generally with new, stable versions, okay, sometimes there can be an issue.
PAUL: Now, loading up the environment variable, so nothing to discuss here, okay? Now, the core part, okay, how exactly Unstructured has done the, part with respect to how everything is there within the partition, okay? So, if you remember, in the last class with respect to docklings.
PAUL: In Docklings, one of the major class was, like, Document Converter. Very specifically, if you remember.
PAUL: Like, for every type of task, you will be using that document converter class.
PAUL: Yes? Similarly here, partition is there.
PAUL: Okay, so, see, guys, the terms will change. It means that under partition, every type of file, like, reading operation, okay, writing operation, everything that you can do.
PAUL: So, partition is always, like, using partition, you will be handling every type of file. So right now, okay, so let me just do a quick import, and let me talk a little bit with respect to the partition function.
PAUL: So, the partition function is basically the universal entry point for document processing in unstructured. It means that at any point of time, okay, if you want to work with any different type of file formats, so you need to always start with the partition function.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, partition is just like the document converter of doc. Very similar. It means that through that, we always use it.
PAUL: Now, coming to the part, okay, what are the different type of element types, that it can extract? Title, narrative text.
PAUL: table, list item, header, footer, text, okay? So, based on structured elements from any type of document, by default, these things are detected. So, let's start with an example where the idea is basically to load some type of file.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, there is a sample.html file, which we have in our sample documents folder, so I think within this, some type of sample document…
PAUL: Okay, your sample.html, which we have.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the actual file.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: So, first of all, let me just pass the path. So, this says… okay, now in the next step, can you see that using partition, I am actually reading the file?
PAUL: Now, this function will automatically detect what is the file type, okay, and based on that, like, automatically whatever the logic that needs to be applied, okay, behind the scenes, because there are a lot of dependency packages also.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, let's just print exactly what is there based on the different type of elements that we have.
PAUL: That's so, yes.
PAUL: So, right now, if you look into some, the different type of information that has been extracted from the HTML file, with respect to the tags. Okay, so as you, as I very specifically told that the title, narrative, text, table, list item, so different type of elements are there. So, for that very specifically, directly, you can access them.
PAUL: Okay, with element underscore time. So, directly, all the elements, you can enumerate. So, this is a really good thing at any point of time, if you look, if you want to have a very specific look into the structure of any type of file. Based on that, you can directly look. So, right here, the title is coming, what is the narrative text.
PAUL: Then title 1.1. Similarly, if there are other titles, all the titles will be listed.
PAUL: So, in this way, and I feel that, structure is somehow much more organized as compared to doglets.
PAUL: Okay, like, the way that you show the result, it's more powerful as compared to docklings. When docklings, it's somewhere to, I will say, towards the simpler side.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: Okay, now this is all the information with respect to our HTML file that we had, okay? Now, going forward.
PAUL: there will be some type of metadata also that we can always look into, so that's why understanding element metadata. Each element has a rich metadata attached to it. Now, the idea is basically to access every element, and based on that, if you try to get it. So, right now, the focus is only on title elements.
PAUL: Now, you can see, I'm looping over all the elements, and very specifically, I'm getting very specifically the title. Okay, now, if title elements are available, then first underscore title is equal to title element with zero the index, okay?
PAUL: So, let's look into the first title that we have.
PAUL: And right now, these are few of the metadata that is coming from each of the elements.
PAUL: So, really, the parsing, the way that it does. So, like, automatically, can you see the file name, the file type, the file directory, the language which has been detected, last modified, okay, and then comes category depth, which is based on the structure of HTML.
PAUL: Okay? The most nested more nested structure will be available. Based on that, the depth will increase. Now, element-wise metadata.
PAUL: I have already told you the role of metadata, okay, at any point of time, if you want to do any type of filter operation.
PAUL: But, like, element-wise.
PAUL: Very specifically. Now, this thing is a little bit new as compared to directly in Docklings, if you try to compare it.
PAUL: Aruno is asking, is this better than BS4 Scrapper? BS4 means beautiful soap, are you referring to?
PAUL: We can read your scene.
PAUL: So very specifically, like, in TalkLink, few features are not there. The idea is to explore those features. As simple as that. At the end of the day, reading an HTML file, the same things can be done with any type of frameworks, or without any frameworks also.
PAUL: purely if you want to read just HTML files. Okay, now the idea was to export that particular metadata, so very specific data, that's why I gave this particular example.
PAUL: Now, so filter elements by type. So, so, at any point of time, when you need a specific content from any type of document, so based on that, we have created a simple function. Going forward, I'll be using this function. So, you can use different type of element count, the distribution, with respect to document. Now, these things, when I'm doing, it's actually document understanding.
PAUL: It means that analyzing the document at every point of time.
PAUL: we keep document stats with us, like, okay, now, in this document, so very specific, like, how many paragraphs are there, how many tokens are there. Okay, now in that way, you should always create your own stats.
PAUL: So, it's very, very important. So, in this way, you can actually create much more vibrant metadata, because at the end of the day, whenever, once you have completed your mean parsing logic, okay, so what is the next step?
PAUL: Creative chunks, Yes, once you have done the core parsing mechanism, what will be the next step?
PAUL: to create channels, no.
PAUL: Once chunks are available, then only, like, with that particular metadata, you will be adding it in the vector table.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, based on that, so this is basically the analyze element.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, I'm getting okay, so there are total 5 titles, 1 table, narrative text as 6, and the list item that we have is very specifically 8.
PAUL: Chunks, embedding, vector DB, retriever, chain, invoke, yes, pretty much. That is the flow. Noise removal is the first step that you have to do it, which… that's a thing that we cannot include in the chain, but it's a must-do task with respect to data preprocessing.
PAUL: So here, looking into very specific type of elements right now, so, exactly with respect to narrative text, what are the things? So, these are, like, paragraphs, if you really think about, okay, the narrative text, which is very specifically mentioned, like, we, total 6 were there, so based on that.
PAUL: Right now, I'm just, looking into… I have printed out not all of them, very specifically, I have taken the index till 5. Okay, so based on that, I'm showing you, okay, now, within this, very specifically, these are done.
PAUL: Now, see, now, this is a little bit different. How many of you know HTML tag parsing?
PAUL: HTML tag that, like, in Beautiful Soup, anybody has used Beautiful Soup, where you parse very specifically the tag name at any point of time, and then actually you look into the information. So, this particular way of hand structure is not using tags.
PAUL: Internally, it uses few tags, okay, to understand that, but directly, you are not passing any tags.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: Not in the,
PAUL: Next step with respect to tables, so very specifically, last time, if you remember, one table was found.
PAUL: So, let's try to access the table. At any point of time, is instance, and very specifically, narrative tests that we have passed. This time, we'll be passing the table, and let's try to look into what is the information which is available in the table with respect to
PAUL: the metadata also. So, table 1, feature description uses, use case OCR, character reader for scanned documents, image, table extraction.
PAUL: Okay, so now this is the information with respect to the table. Now, if I try to open this file, and really, if I try to analyze it, okay, so sample.html, let me just open it in Finder.
PAUL: Okay, and I will try to open this in browser.
PAUL: Okay, can you see, see this document parser? Now, this is the table that has come up.
PAUL: Very cool.
PAUL: Okay, now, OCR support.
PAUL: Okay, now the way that it has done in Doclinks directly, if you look into it, prints in Markdown format with respect to table. But right now, here, very specifically, we have not used any markdown.
PAUL: So, based on that, okay, so OCR support optical. Now, let's try to analyze, okay? So, first of all, a feature description that is coming.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, this part, use case, OCR support, optical character recognition. Okay, now this part, which is there.
PAUL: Then, after that image, they will extraction.
PAUL: Okay, so this part, can you see, after images, table extraction directly came here, so, like…
PAUL: It is getting the text, but actually, like, maintaining the structure. Because actually, right now, I'm directly looking into the data. Based on the data, alright, this part looks good.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, the last word is coming with respect to presentations. Okay, here I can see. So, yes, with respect to that, particular, I can say, information which has been extracted.
PAUL: I will say that, yes, the core text, which I was actually looking for, it has extracted that.
PAUL: Okay, later on, if you want, at any point of time, you can convert that into Markdown. Okay? Layout… so, right now, very specifically, I'm looking into a tag information.
PAUL: So, really, that layout doesn't matter. We know that it is within a table alignment.
PAUL: Okay, so from that, you can… anybody, if it's a table element, you can convert it into a markdown table. It's not a big thing.
PAUL: The core idea was to detect the table, at least. You have to understand that part. I hope everybody understands that. Right now, I'm accessing a tag, so within that tag, whatever is the information, that has come.
PAUL: Please let me know this part.
PAUL: Because right now, really, like, if it could not detect the structure or the layout, how it can recognize that it was a table?
PAUL: So, don't focus on that, the structure right here. I, like, this particular information, I can take it. With respect to the tag, I can pass it through a markdown, and based on that, rendering can be done. So, don't get confused. Right now, this was the actual information, okay?
PAUL: Alright, now, let's focus a little bit with respect to partition strategies.
PAUL: Now, partition strategies. So, initially, we have passed only an HTML file. Now, going forward, the idea is to explore different type of file formats.
PAUL: After that, how you will read this content as table? It is a table. Why you will read it as a table, Ashish?
PAUL: in the HTML,
PAUL: Okay, so very specific, if I click this one, okay, and if you try to do some type of inspect, can you see this TD?
PAUL: Based on that only it will detect, no?
PAUL: So don't think that the table information is lost.
PAUL: Hold it.
PAUL: So, really doesn't matter so much. If you bring this same table, copy-paste that, and bring it, then also it will detect.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, in the HTML file, there are very specific tags with respect to table creation.
PAUL: I hope everyone gets it. We don't pass those tags, but it detects, based on that.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now, so unstructured offers different type of partitioning strategies to balance speed and accuracy. Now, this is one good thing that I feel very unique with respect to unstructured.
PAUL: Similarly, like, working with different type of layouts, the same functionality is available in Dropling also, but here, more options are there. Okay, now, first of all, there are different type of strategies when you are working with partition.
PAUL: So, first of all, the default one, automatically. Okay, now, it will detect. So, auto, if I'm talking about, so it can pick up fast, high resolution, OCR only. So, generally, by default, it tries to pick up fast most of the times.
PAUL: Then comes high resolution. To work with high resolution, you need a separate
PAUL: I think a package which is required in your system, which is referred to as popular. Okay, that needs to be installed. Then comes OCR only. Now, if you remember, what is the default OCR in docklings that we have discussed?
PAUL: Partitioning is the way of loading documents in unstructured MS already told, please look into the top part of the notebook.
PAUL: A hurry, you can make that, and probably based on that, because it is possible, the way that you were telling.
PAUL: At any point of time.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, with respect to auto, we will start with the default one. The idea is to load some type of PDF, and based on that, we'll be looking into that. Okay? So, it was the default OCR will dockling, it is Rapid OCR, okay? And then you have
PAUL: different OCR engines, from where you can pick up Tesseract OCR, EZ OCR, the other OCR engines were there. Okay.
PAUL: Now, here, very specifically, like, unstructured comes with parallel OCR. So, a different OCR at any point of time, but yes, the core idea at any point of time for optical character recognition, the same task can be done.
PAUL: Like, paddle is also a famous project. Yesterday, I have shown you, if you remember, in GitHub, so a lot of stars are there. So now, this particular project, very specifically, they have used.
PAUL: Now, the idea is basically to read a PDF, so that's why I'm just simply passing in path, okay, of our previous document. Okay, so the documentpaper.pdf, this is the path, and right now.
PAUL: Let's look into whether the document exists or not.
PAUL: Okay, now I'll be looking into these type of partitioning strategies. Now, at any point of time, if you change the strategy, now the question comes, do you want speed or do you want accuracy in simple terms?
PAUL: Okay, so fast, if I'm talking about quick processing, no models. It means that default, some type of basic framework which has been used behind the scenes. Okay, basic frameworks, right? For example, directly if you want to read in PDF. Okay, so what is the most basic package?
PAUL: new PDF is there, pipe PDF is there, it means that directly using the raw package.
PAUL: PDF miner, so, so many simple packages are there, using which you can read PDFs.
PAUL: But if you want something, okay, much higher, then you need to download some type of models, because very specifically, if you try to execute high-res, okay, it will tell you that you need this particular, popular package within your system, which will help you to access, different type of models.
PAUL: What is the definition of slow? Like, yes, it is with respect to time complexity that we do our referral.
PAUL: Okay, fast means easy to access at any point of time. High resolution means internally, some type of model that will be used. It can be layout-based models. Okay, OCR-based models. Okay, I hope you get that.
PAUL: So, first of all, the file already exists, as I can see here.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, very specifically, I'm starting with the strategy auto. It means that, by default, the FASC which is being implemented.
PAUL: So, here, with respect to the document that I have, see, the loading of the document I have done here. Now, once the document is available, I am passing this, okay, to this partition. At any point of time, I told you will just, like, doc converter, okay? Document converter in docking.
PAUL: So, using this, you can node a file, as simple as that. So, partition automatically detects the file type, and based on that, it will apply your parsing logic.
PAUL: Now, strategy is equal to auto, okay? Now, based on that, the time that we have taken, so that's where the idea is to calculate that particular time.
PAUL: And we will be looking into the element distribution of this particular document. Last time, we looked into the HTML document, this time the document has changed to PDF.
PAUL: Okay? So, let's see.
PAUL: Alright, time taken close to 3.94 seconds, element extracted close to 276, and really, like, like, this is a PDF, so for sure,
PAUL: Based on the footers, 10 footers that you have, list items, 4 narrative texts, really, 75 texts…
PAUL: 86 and 101 that you have.
PAUL: Okay, now, yes, the speeds will be different in every system. In my system, it will be different. In your system, it will be different.
PAUL: Okay, so we got directly in the PDF file. What is the structure? Okay, now, this particular structure is only maintained by unstructured, very specifically. In other frameworks, generally, they don't sync.
PAUL: Okay, now we have done, the reading of the PDF, we looked into the elements of the PDF.
PAUL: Now, if I am, moving ahead with fast, so very specifically, okay, now, the core packages. Now, the idea is that here, simply.
PAUL: If you look into, so 0.85 seconds, so somehow I feel that this is faster, but, with respect to extraction somewhere, so numbers might change. So, here, Title 101, Title 101, text 86, text 86, narrative text 75,
PAUL: Here's 75 with respect to footers, 10 and less. So I feel that, yes, in this case particularly, like, both are working fine. Okay, so my auto strategy, okay, and the other one, the fast strategy for now.
PAUL: And generally, like, quick processing without any type of machine learning models. Okay, so machine learning models come inbuilt, few models are available, but few other models are also available, that you need to do the pre-installation.
PAUL: Okay, but, if I'm really talking with respect to the difference, 0.85 seconds, and if you try to compare this.
PAUL: with 3.94. Like, it can be close to 3.5 also, but really, like, most of the times, I can say that fast works really good, okay? We don't use the auto strategy. Fast is really good, but the quality of the document should be based on digital text.
PAUL: Okay, like, digital text-based documents, it works really good, because for these type of documents, you know that PDF Miner, the actual package behind the scenes which is used is
PAUL: PDF minor.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the actual package.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, that is being used by Unstructured. Similarly, like, every framework is using a different core PDF package.
PAUL: Similarly, like, Unstructured totally relies on third-party packages for every type of task.
PAUL: Whereas Dockling has few inbuilt modules for different type of file formats. But unstructured, that's why very specifically during the installation, we mentioned the different type of file formats within a bracket. Okay, and based on that, the installation takes place.
PAUL: Now, similarly, I will move to, higher resolution. Okay, now, this is where few of you might get errors. Okay, even I might get error. But, let's look into.
PAUL: Okay, so… Now…
PAUL: For high resolution, it will take time, because very specifically, based on machine learning models, okay, and you need to install some package.
PAUL: Okay, so warning, low language specified, default to English, the max size parameter is deprecated, fine, this is a warning.
PAUL: Let's look, like…
PAUL: Okay, it depends upon system to system.
PAUL: If…
PAUL: PDF IN infer, so very specifically, if you don't have this particular package, do the installation. Okay, pip install, if you are missing on this one.
PAUL: Okay, so even… so, for me, so very specifically, okay, as you can see here, the time.
PAUL: Okay, now this is based on machine learning model which has been used. The time taken was 63.62 seconds, element extracted. Can I see that right now the element extraction has increased?
PAUL: As compared to last time.
PAUL: Previously, it was around 276, I feel. Okay, so if you remember, this was the number, 276. Now, the number of elements extracted has been changed. So, last time, very specifically, if you look into headers, I don't feel headers was there.
PAUL: Only footer that was used very specifically, but this time, yes, headers have been used.
PAUL: Okay, then comes the other things which have increased here.
PAUL: Okay, so somewhere around, like, every figure has changed.
PAUL: Footer 10, list item 4.
PAUL: Okay, list item has been 20. Footer, it has decreased to 2 this time.
PAUL: Title on 1, text 36…
PAUL: Okay, so here, text 192. So now, based on this, because right now there is specifically a different model that has been… that has been used, and I can say here the accuracy is really high, but the speed will always be low. So generally, I feel that
PAUL: Yet you should not use high resolution at any point of time, because really, to read a PDF, 63 seconds
PAUL: nobody will accept such type of solutions. If you are working with a batching-based solution, it's fine. It means that during a certain time, you run a Chrome job for all this particular… like, generally, the number of documents will be in thousands.
PAUL: Even in a batch. So, like, for one document, if it takes 63 seconds, just multiply it by 1000 at any point of time.
PAUL: This is a memory-intensive task also.
PAUL: Elements refer to the tags who are sharma. How elements can be words?
PAUL: Okay? Now, people, see, the first thing is this one. Okay, you need to install this package, please do install it if it is missing in your system. Okay, and I think everybody can do it.
PAUL: Ctrl-C. Okay, open your terminal, just paste it here, you have to restart the cell.
PAUL: Victorious.
PAUL: Okay, so in my case, it was already available.
PAUL: Okay? And, very specifically, the installation of Poplar. Anybody is getting that Poplar?
PAUL: GSMS, it is high accuracy, so it's basically a trade-off between speed and accuracy.
PAUL: Yes, anybody is getting that, popular installation, because generally in Mac, we do brew install popular.
PAUL: Okay, similarly for Windows, you need to do the installation.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to… now, see, this is a third-party package, nothing that I can do.
PAUL: Okay, but yes, popular installation is required.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, I know for Mac, it is, like, brev install popular. You can directly install it in your system. Okay.
PAUL: For Mac, I'm pasting it in the chat, directly. Simply the name of the package. On Ubuntu and Debian, it is sudo apt gate install popular utils.
PAUL: Okay, so now this is the command, very specifically with respect to Linux.
PAUL: Because popular with Windows, really, that part I've not checked, but let me check. Popular with Windows…
PAUL: I'm gonna stall you.
PAUL: popular binaries are there very specifically. Okay, so…
PAUL: Download popular binaries packaged with this one, but really, this is old, 3 days ago, package.sh.
PAUL: Popularly packaged.
PAUL: Alright, few windows are there, but again, I don't feel popular windows. Now, this is one Ripple you can actually look into, okay?
PAUL: It's fine, probably, like, in Windows, probably a restart is required, or sometime it happens.
PAUL: Okay, so if anybody is getting that, okay, from here you can look into. So, let me do an Windows installation.
PAUL: For BreeWAN, Linux is pretty much straightforward.
PAUL: Okay, so I think Osh Bar… dishes…
PAUL: Okay, the popular releases, alright.
PAUL: Because actually, when I look into the releases, so very specifically, from here, you need to get it. Exactly which one you are looking for based on your operating system.
PAUL: So, release 25 is there. Okay, and now, based on that, yes, binaries have been provided. So, very specifically for Poplar, okay, now, this is the report that you can refer into. I'm sharing the link.
PAUL: Okay, ESP, pimple, unstructured, that is fine.
PAUL: that is… There won't be any type of issues there.
PAUL: Breeze install popular uttils? Okay, Momark. Yes, for Mac, it's straightforward, but for Windows.
PAUL: Because in Windows, once you have the zip, you have to do an unzipping operation, okay? And then you have to add it to your environment variable.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes.
PAUL: those things that you have to do, very specifically for Windows. So if you are… if you are a Windows user, you need to follow those steps. Okay, now…
PAUL: directly the manual…
PAUL: Because anybody is using Conta, because if anybody is using Conta, in Quanta also, there is a direct package, the popular package.
PAUL: Okay, so now this is where actually Conda comes in handy. Conda install.
PAUL: Conda first, popular packages there. So, if anybody is working with Conda, they can directly install it in Windows also, the easiest way.
PAUL: Now, anybody who's using Chocolaty in Windows, anybody who is using Chocolaty, please let me know.
PAUL: If you are using Chocolaty in Windows, okay, then Choco install poplar is also there.
PAUL: Okay, it means that based on different type of packages is there. Even Scoop, package manager, if you're using, inside Scoop, also, you are popular. So, in Windows C, take the binary, add it to your environment variable.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Because in Windows, it's a little bit tricky, but the idea is that if you have Choco, it becomes, much easier.
PAUL: Okay, everybody, please try to do it. Okay. I think, for how many of you, it's working? Poplar, please let me know.
PAUL: So, somebody's asking, what is popular? Again, an open source, like, PDF rendering library.
PAUL: Okay, Poplar is an open-source PDF rendering library. So now you're installing with Conda, okay, fine, not working as of now. For Mac user, will you install Poplar?
PAUL: I've already shared the commands in the chat, okay, so in Notion also, I will add it.
PAUL: So just wait. Notion, let me just open Notion.
PAUL: Okay, so… light batches…
PAUL: I will add few of the commands. Based on that, you can look into your Notion.
PAUL: Now, one was…
PAUL: Bree will install, okay. For Mac, I feel that this is really good, and you can work with this one.
PAUL: Then, for Linux…
PAUL: It was, APT gate install popular utility, okay? Then, for Windows.
PAUL: One option is directly install it with Conda, okay?
PAUL: Then the other option is installing with Choco, the chocolatey backlit Package Manager in Windows. Then there is Scoop.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And then finally, the other package that you have…
PAUL: Okay, because I think I have pasted major wave.
PAUL: or basically the GitHub, okay? From there, you will be getting the binary.
PAUL: So, I think… I can…
PAUL: Alright, now this is the actual Windows binary that you have.
PAUL: So, from here, please check out the release section.
PAUL: So, whichever way in Windows you feel, please do it, okay? I feel that.
PAUL: Windows part is a little bit tricky, really. Nothing that we can do.
PAUL: It's just because the support is towards the LASS side. For Linux and Mac, it's a little bit towards the easier side.
PAUL: I added in the path, it is working. Probably after that, in Windows, restart another scheme, that really meets.
PAUL: Thorav is asking, why not pip install python popular? Try to do it, I have no issue in that.
PAUL: The idea is that popular should be available. Once popular is available, then you can actually do an, directly pip install Python popular.
PAUL: Okay, but the idea is that these binaries should be available in your system. That's the main thing.
PAUL: Yeah, so this is pretty much the part with respect to… popular installations.
PAUL: So follow this, because this is just like a third-party package. Nothing we can do very specifically, it is used by Unstructured, so you need to follow that.
PAUL: And generally, I will prefer, like, in Windows, try to use Conda Chocolatey, because it's a much easier way as getting the binary, doing that type of stuff.
PAUL: Create a new environment, it's a good practice always, and then on top of that.
PAUL: Okay, so at any point of time, even for Conda, okay, please try to do it in a very specific virtual environment.
PAUL: Karen, you're asking, can you repeat the popular part? You just need to install Poplar in your system. For that, I have already told the steps for Mac, Linux, and Windows.
PAUL: So, for how many of you it is working, for a few people it might… I think.
PAUL: Now, it is asking for Tesseract. Alright.
PAUL: That's alright, because in my system, The Surat is there.
PAUL: Okay, yes, I do have a Tesseract.
PAUL: Previously, I have been using.
PAUL: Okay, alright, yes.
PAUL: For installing, again, Tasarat in your system, really, like, you need to install a lot of things.
PAUL: How many of you, in your system is telling you can do the installation of Tesseract, so Tesseract…
PAUL: for Windows, Okay.
PAUL: Again, EXE file, you will get it directly, I think.
PAUL: Tesseract, OCR from here.
PAUL: Somehow, the actual source code… Okay, and if you look into the releases part.
PAUL: It's somewhere with respect to .exe and some other assets that you will be getting.
PAUL: TJ, your error is with respect to Hugging Fish.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And in Mac, for Tesla, this is pretty much we've installed Tesla not.
PAUL: Mac, it's easy. Windows also, it's easy. Let me just look for install Tesseract Windows…
PAUL: Because this is the actual official, refer of Tesseract OCR,
PAUL: Okay, because in my case, yes, it is available, but in your case, I think in Windows, again, if you have Chocolaty, Choco installed Tesseract is there, or, okay, from University of Maine, alright, let me open the link.
PAUL: Okay, now, from here, you'll be getting the link with respect to EXE. Can you see here? 64-bit Windows? Okay, please use this link. I'm sharing it in the chat. Just click on the link, and it will open. You don't need to copy-paste, just click the link, and it will open in a browser. Please download this .exe.
PAUL: What tesseractose here?
PAUL: Okay, fine, if you're using Conda, I have no issues. Using Conda also, you can do it.
PAUL: Okay, once you have done that, please add it to your main path, wherever that exe file is there.
PAUL: Once you have done that, add to the path, it will be up and working.
PAUL: Yes, Brave installed Tesseract OCR.
PAUL: Okay, so… Now, brave installed is only Tesseract. I'm sharing the command for Mac also in the chat.
PAUL: Okay? So the commands that I have shared very specifically for Tesseract.
PAUL: I will add it here also.
PAUL: Okay, just the racked.
PAUL: Tricerat is basically the OCR engine.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: For Mac, preview installed Taker Act is there. Then, for Windows, you will be having the .exe file from this particular location.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: After, getting it, please add to path. Very, very important.
PAUL: Anybody a Linux user?
PAUL: Linux users can use, basically, sudo apta install, Tesseract, OCR, all. Now, these are all the major packages with respect to OCR engine.
PAUL: Mac user brief will work yes, we've installed Tesseract.
PAUL: by default, the language support comes with English. If you need some other language support, then very specifically, provincial at LAN.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the… another…
PAUL: package that you can actually check. It gives you multi-language support.
PAUL: Now, people are asking, PIP install PyTestrect, why not this?
PAUL: First, you need the binary. Without the binary, getting the package, what is the use?
PAUL: Kindly enable the copy option. So, you need to probably downgrade your Zoom version. In the later Zoom version, the copy option is not enabled. It's just security. You probably need to downgrade to some at least 6 months or 8 months back.
PAUL: Okay, I have added majorly everything in Notion. From Notion, you can directly get everything.
PAUL: all the major commands. And really, like, for high resolution, okay, you need a little bit. The dependency was there, because Tesseract is always there in my system, so we thought about
PAUL: But really, like, this type of resolute, working with high resolution really takes a lot of time. So, please check, because sometimes a restart might be required, very specifically for Windows users. Linux and Mac users, no issue, but in Windows, sometimes it can create
PAUL: Ami Chen is asking, how can we use Quinn and Mistralos here?
PAUL: No, there is no support for that.
PAUL: If you're working with an OCR engine, it can be totally separate. It's not necessary you use it with unstructured, or docklings. They will always give you very specific support.
PAUL: Now, you need to bring your own implementation of Mistral, okay, probably an API-based, or, like, for DeepSeek OCR, okay, and then you need to pass it through this pipeline.
PAUL: So here, the idea is that you will be reading the PDF using instruction, and if you want to move some external APIs, you can do it.
PAUL: Working fine for me, working fine, working fine? Alright, R is getting, so generally Mac users are done. Anybody stuck? Please let me know.
PAUL: There is no EXE for popular, no, Abhishek, there is no EXE for popular.
PAUL: See, now these are simple installation issues, but yes, the complexity is there, because at the end of the day.
PAUL: Okay, you need to add it to path, sometimes after adding to path, you might, have some problem. Okay, like, the path is not getting detected, you might need a restart.
PAUL: Okay, like, okay, working fine, working fine, working fine. Many people told, but what about Windows users? I know majorly all Mac users, there won't be any problem.
PAUL: Cinewaz is telling installed, but getting not recognized in Mac.
PAUL: No, this is fine. Asma Sultana, there is no issues. I think zero text title, this is the rendering issue, the one that you were showing.
PAUL: It's not a package-related issue.
PAUL: to which path we need to add your name, where I think the path that comes under system variable agent.
PAUL: There you have to add it.
PAUL: I'm Windows user initialization installation field. Really, like, probably… if you want, very specifically, you can try this, probably after the class, because you might need to do a restart. So, for now, skip this, as simple as that. Okay?
PAUL: Okay, so later on, please look into… because the steps are pretty much clear. You need to install this and this one. Now, if you really spent a lot of time here.
PAUL: Okay? The idea is just skip this cell for now, and later on, focus only on the installation part. Just be sure all the paths are added. Your Tesserith path needs to be added, your popular path needs to be added, and these are only for Windows users, nothing that we can do.
PAUL: Okay, you have to follow those structures.
PAUL: Yes, Kartik.
PAUL: The high resolution is extracting the tables, so at any point of time, you can look into the tables. There is no issue.
PAUL: Code part where we need to add the path. You need to add the path in your environment variable in Windows.
PAUL: See, guys, at least be familiar of working with your operating system. How many of you know the meaning of adding paths?
PAUL: When I say adding path, it means that you need to add it to your system variables.
PAUL: I hope you get it.
PAUL: Alright, fine. Okay, now, let's… I will proceed ahead.
PAUL: Okay, so I won't be using, very specifically, the, this particular high resolution, because it's really time-taking, and it takes a lot of time for execution. Later on, you can test it out.
PAUL: The idea is very simple. Whenever you are working in production, you need to pick up the trade-off, okay? The trade-off here is simply, like, speed or accuracy at the end of the deal.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on that, you have to take the decision. Do you want something, okay, which is having higher accuracy, but in the end of the day, the latency is really very, very high.
PAUL: Okay, so it's rainy, so I feel that more than, like, 50X at least.
PAUL: Now, the idea is to look into this very specific strategies, and right now, the implementation, so two strategies only I have taken, so the auto and the fast strategy.
PAUL: So, right here, I'm passing all the elements that have been detected, display the first 10 elements for a partition result.
PAUL: And then, on top of the elements I'm doing, and based on that, let me look into. And two strategies I am using, the strategy name and the… the strategy auto and the first. Auto is the, I can say.
PAUL: Auto is good, but again, sometimes PDF finder, there can be some type of issues. And based on that, the initial top 5 elements that I am showing you, which is the text, the title, again we have text, then again we have title, then we have the version.
PAUL: And from FAST, really, if you try to look into… the amount of information is pretty much same. Here, some numbers, title, LC.SC in the text part, with respect to archive, title, the docklink technical report, and the version 1.1.
PAUL: So, very specifically, if you, check this part, I feel that, yes, the results are very, very similar. Okay, there is not a lot of difference if you actually go with auto strategy or fast strategy.
PAUL: It is just the change of the package, behind the scenes. So, what is the package? So, it's always remember the package is PDFminer.6. Okay, at any point of time, you need to install this package. If you don't have this package in your system, okay, it will throw you an error.six.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the actual project. Don't only pass PDF minor. Okay,
PAUL: Yeah, because PDF finder is the older version, so for Python 3, with .6 support is there. So, very specifically, I've mentioned about this in requirement.txt also.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so let's move ahead, okay?
PAUL: Now, like, in unstructured, okay, so as per documentation, there are, different type of file formats which are supported, just like image, audio, and other stuff.
PAUL: Now, here,
PAUL: PDF part, we have already looked into. Okay, now the idea is to, look into some others.
PAUL: type of file format, okay? So, let's start with HTML documents. Also, I feel that we have already gone through.
PAUL: Okay, then comes working with markdown documents. Very similarly, the strategy, like, partition.md at any point of time, if you want to pass it, so very specifically, you need to pass that. So always remember.
PAUL: It's not about working. If I want high resolution, I don't take it from unstructured.
PAUL: Okay, I will be using my own implementation.
PAUL: why I will use a behind-the-scenes Tesseract, or Poplar. I know there are better solutions in the market, so the idea is to stick to them.
PAUL: Now, Unstructured provides you with the direct support of working with Tesseract, but it's totally up to you. Do you want to use that? Okay, I don't feel that it should be used.
PAUL: Okay, because there are better techniques right now.
PAUL: So, similarly, at any point of time, so partition underscore MD, so again, from partition, I'm calling it, so you have to pass the name of the file, and based on that, it will read the entire file, and you can get all your elements also.
PAUL: Okay? Now, analyze element is our mean function at any point of time, because MD element is the actual data that you are getting. Okay?
PAUL: And then, within that, we are actually always focusing on the element. No other library actually focus on elements in such a way, very specifically, only unstructured does it. This is one uniqueness, if I'm talking about.
PAUL: Then, coming to the markdown structure, very specifically, which has been extracted. So you can look into, like, the major title, the document parsing, best practices, what is there in Title I, then what is there in Narrative Text 1, then again in Title II, then what are the four different type of list items.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, very specifically, if you look here.
PAUL: in this particular structure of Markdown, so sample.md.
PAUL: Now, this is exactly how the file looks like.
PAUL: I did.
PAUL: Now, based on that, I have picked up…
PAUL: So always have a look into your original files, it will always give you an idea.
PAUL: So, right now, based on this, if you really look into here, okay, I feel that…
PAUL: Okay, out of the total number of elements, okay, so very specifically, yes, two tables are extracted right now. See, here I am not printing out the tables, but I hope you get that.
PAUL: Okay, so in this particular structure, I'm taking the top 15. So initially, like, okay, table was detected at a later point, but yes, two tables are there, which are actually coming.
PAUL: Similarly now, this is a new markdown string that I have taken into account. Okay, and directly you can pass markdown strings also. Now, this is one good thing. At any point of time, you can pass a single piece of text within that text. It can be any format. And so, for example, I have taken in this particular string a markdown syntax.
PAUL: And that, I am passing it to mark, to basically your partition underscoreMD.
PAUL: So, the idea is that within that variable, you should be having some type of markdown information. If there is no markdown information, simply, like, it will throw an error.
PAUL: Okay? Now, here also, the main title. Okay, now this is coming. With that narrative text after this, this is the introduction paragraph.
PAUL: Section 1. The idea is, basically, when I'm showing you this structure, I have manually defined it, so that you can relate it to your original Markdown file. So, exactly what is this? Like, title section 1. So, simply, like, this becomes your title, then this becomes your another title.
PAUL: After your title, again, like, the narrative text, so with two different bullet points that you have. Okay, so that comes as your narrative text. So, at any point of time, so the actual paragraph is your narrative text and text. Two different type of text categories are there.
PAUL: Okay, now, very specifically, can you see here, text dev follow?
PAUL: Now, this part. So, really, I feel that for this type of, like, though it has extracted the information, but correct parsing logic has not been applied. The idea is that, okay.
PAUL: The… you need to detect some type of code.
PAUL: And really, right now, unstructured cannot do it. It means that you need a custom function at any point of time.
PAUL: Because here, it's simply treating as deafollow, but do you really think, this is part of text?
PAUL: How many of you think this is part of text? This is not text, this is actually a programming.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on that, you have to write a very specific, I can say, chunking logic, okay, where something comes here, very specifically. This can be separated at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, you have to detect, like, okay, now, what is the language? And based on that, you need to retain that entire function, okay, or probably, it can be a class also sometimes.
PAUL: Okay, now this needs to be handled. So, by default, unstructured doesn't handle it for you.
PAUL: So, you have to always under that.
PAUL: Yes, I'm not talking about recursive characters text splitter. Very specifically, if I'm talking about, to handle code scenarios, like, you need a different type of changing mechanism.
PAUL: Alright, now, the idea is to work with Microsoft documents.
PAUL: Okay, so now let's try to explore a little bit about this.
PAUL: So, very specifically, with respect to, you can see here, unstructured is using which package?
PAUL: It means that it doesn't have a default module. It is using, basically, the Python docx package. Now, again, if you have installed unstructured, but if you don't have this particular package in your system, again, you will get an error.
PAUL: Okay, just be sure this package is available, and I know that, if you have executed that big command upon structure that I provided in the initial installation cell, so this particular package will come.
PAUL: Okay. Now, in this particular cell, exactly what I am doing, the idea was to create some type of sample document, so based on that, I have taken it, and I have just created a
PAUL: a new document, where I'm given the name of sample1.dox. Okay, now, you can bring your own document also. So, I think this is sample1.
PAUL: Okay, I cannot open it, but, if I do it and it will in Finder…
PAUL: So, exactly what is the information that I have tried to build. So, it means that using Python, you can create… okay, and let me just show you exactly how the doc looks like.
PAUL: Can you see it?
PAUL: Simply, like, this is a simple operation where we are just creating our docx file.
PAUL: Now, later on, on top of that, you can simply do parsing. Now, this is a simple file. We can take something like a complex file. You have a file which is referred to as sample.docs. I think sample.docs is there.
PAUL: or only one doc file. Okay, yes, sample.docs is there, and sample1.docs is also there. So now, sample.docs is a much… a technical report is there very specifically. So that also we can pass, so one by one, we'll be passing it.
PAUL: So, first of all, we have created very specifically, and this is the docket's path, okay, where we are saving, right now, the file. So, at every point of time, we'll be creating a new document, and based on that, we'll be saving it. Now, within that document, very specifically, what are the different type of
PAUL: Elements that you have.
PAUL: Okay, so now see, can I say that for every type of file type.
PAUL: Unstructured maintains a very specific type of element structure.
PAUL: Till now, there is not a single library in the market who does it. Only unstructured does it.
PAUL: The idea of recognizing something as title, narrative, text. Okay, now this is where I feel that it is a little bit unique.
PAUL: Okay, as compared to any other. But yes, you have to understand, every time the correct detection, it doesn't happen, because yes, in HTML files, it's much easier by looking into tags, but if you really look into simple text files, really, you cannot get a lot of idea.
PAUL: Yes, docklink is better, even I feel that, okay, you can use docklings, so I use a mixture of docklings and unstructured. It's totally up to you, like, how you are creating that particular example.
PAUL: How do we know which to use? So generally, start your testing with two major libraries, Docklings, and then Unstructured, as simple as that. If you want to go for open source, these are the simplest ones.
PAUL: In unstructured, you always get much more structured information. In Docklink, it's always about the direct text info that you are getting.
PAUL: What are elements? Elements are basically the tags. Akhil, if you remember, we have very specifically created an analyzedElement function.
PAUL: Yes, somewhere around here. Okay, and analyzeElement. Okay, now, defAnalyzeElement. Now, this analyzeElement… this particular function I'm calling for every type of file type.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: So now, using this particular function, you can pass it to any type of partition-based documents. It means that if you are using unstructured, and through partition, you are actually reading a file, then you can analyze the elements.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now let's move to some other type of documents.
PAUL: Okay, so markdown we have already looked into. Let's focus on some type of office-based documents, okay?
PAUL: Now,
PAUL: here, very specifically, if you want to change, okay, and if you want to read very specifically the files. Okay, so partition underscore docs is also there. So, similarly for XLS file also, what we have done, we have simply created an
PAUL: XLS file based on OpenPy XML. Now, unstructured is a dependency. It means that if you don't have this particular package, again, you will get an error, very specifically for XLX files.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, we are creating a workbook. Okay, inside that workbook, we are basically saving all the information.
PAUL: Okay? Yes, in Dockling, they don't follow this elemental structure, which is widely used by unstructured. Okay, but again, the core information of reading at any point of time, we always get it.
PAUL: Okay, now this point, let me just create it. Okay, and now you can see I'm using partition underscore XLS. Similarly, you have your partition underscore docx. Similarly, partition underscore PPTX. At every point of time, you'll be getting this.
PAUL: Now, based on that, again, I'll be reading the document, and let me just look into the different type of elements that we have, and right now, with respect to XLS file, it's pretty much, okay, there is a table, now that table is having category, so simply, if I try to reveal this one, sample1.xls.
PAUL: Here we see that, yes, at the end of the day, it will be treated as a table only.
PAUL: So… Somewhere around.
PAUL: Okay, I hope you get it.
PAUL: Okay, it's really small, I cannot…
PAUL: In math every AD… no problem.
PAUL: Okay, I hope you get what is there in the actual information, yes.
PAUL: Alright, now…
PAUL: How could it handle the formula? If within a send, there is a formula, it will extract that information also.
PAUL: But right here, yes, there has to be a formula. Everybody does it.
PAUL: Every type of framework will do it for you.
PAUL: Now, similarly, with respect to PPTX file also, okay, so similarly, the idea in the first cell, just create it in the next step, just load it.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, you'll be getting, okay, now, unstructured demo, there is a very specific title of document parsing RAG, okay. Now, this one that I have created, again, if I try to open it with respect to PPTX file.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just open it.
PAUL: Yes, something like this, in the PBT, if you really look into.
PAUL: Okay, but always remember, like, if you actually try with some complex, because right now it's pretty much, I'm creating very simple PDF, but if you really want to pass.
PAUL: Okay, some complex. Okay, so let's try to pass something complex here. Okay, for each of the cases, because yes, this is something an easy document, but what about if I try to increase the complexity at any point of time? Okay.
PAUL: So, let's try to do that.
PAUL: with respect to partitioning, what I can do…
PAUL: I'm just looking into this part.
PAUL: table.add, okay. So, let me just take one file, which I have, which is the complex one, sample.copyRelativePath, and let me directly pass it within XLS.
PAUL: Okay, so the XLS file path, as you can see here, now this is there. The idea is to update this particular path.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just update it.
PAUL: Okay? I'm taking a much more complex document, just like last time.
PAUL: Okay, and here, let me just pause this…
PAUL: Okay, the idea is that the variable should be overwritten.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, based on the information which is extracted, So…
PAUL: Here, XLS elements, the number of elements, narrative text 4, table 3, text 2, title 2. Okay?
PAUL: And right now, really, like, see, I'm not printing very specifically all the elements, but looks like, yes, the actual information that I was looking, I'm getting it.
PAUL: So, yes, like, if you remember just, this is the last file that I have taken into account.
PAUL: Okay, and really, it is working pretty great, I can say.
PAUL: How would this add multiple tabs? At any point of time, you can handle tabs. Tabs, basically, I think, are you referring to sheets?
PAUL: Huh? Multitab dependency, something like that? Are you referring?
PAUL: Yes, everybody can handle that. You can pass very specific sheet names, and based on that. Every framework can do, it's nothing that is fancy. Okay.
PAUL: Now, similarly, let me just change the PDF file. Now, I will be using a very complex PPT, which is not created by PowerPoint presentation, okay? So, somewhere here around, I think, I will be having one document, sample.pdx, okay? Now, this particular PPT that I have.
PAUL: Okay, so if you remember, something like this. Okay, now this is not actually created using, PowerPoint.
PAUL: Okay, so I think there will be some type of rendering issues. Even, like, in Mac, I do have such problems.
PAUL: Now, very specifically, let me just change this path.
PAUL: Okay, so PPTH… But… Let's see here…
PAUL: Okay, so sample documents, now let me pass sample one.
PAUL: Everybody has that, please analyze the file.
PAUL: Okay, now I will try to do this. And right now, based on the information that I have.
PAUL: Okay, really, if you, really look into, I don't feel that everything that is getting extracted.
PAUL: Okay, yes, because this PPT is not built using, very specifically, like, PPTX, it was from Canva, that's why the information based on the result. If you really look into
PAUL: what is there in the PDF, so if I try to bring it here…
PAUL: Okay, so a lot of things are there, how it works, AI-powered rack, technology, multi-model intelligence, so really, it is missing a lot of things.
PAUL: That I can directly say. So, yes.
PAUL: we always face problems. It means that most of the packages are by default, because there is no such package, we know that
PAUL: In Canva, exactly, behind the scenes during the export, what type of export that they are doing. But yes, we have seen that, yes, there are problems with the PPTX export of Canva. Okay, it becomes very hard to read it at any point of time. Few things that can be extracted, but again, not everything that I can see.
PAUL: Always remember, it's always good to work with PowerPoint-based files which are directly created in Microsoft PowerPoint. If you try to create it in some other place, and if you try to bring it here, there will be always some type of problem, I can say.
PAUL: For this type of data, you can use OCR. Yes, you can use OCR. OCR you can use at any point of time. But generally, for digital text, it is not preferred to use OCR.
PAUL: You have to understand.
PAUL: Okay, if you have high-quality digital text, do you think that you need OCR at every point of time, just to read it?
PAUL: You don't require that. But somehow, if you feel that, okay, I don't have access to any package, or anything, at that particular point of time, OCR is your final, I can say result. But majorly, I know for every type of file type, there are open source packages using which you can directly do it.
PAUL: Mostly for scanned, yes. Generally, for handwritten documents, I prefer it. For scanned documents, I prefer it. Directly on top of digital text, I don't prefer.
PAUL: Sk is asking, dockling or unstructured, which is a better job at presentations? Both are bad.
PAUL: Okay, both are bad, rather than… the idea is that when you are taking the export, use a PDF. At least, I have seen the results with PDFs are much better.
PAUL: Okay, don't take an export of PPTX. PPTX from Canva, Gamma, everywhere, it creates a problem. The idea is, if you're working with PDF, at least you get better information.
PAUL: Alright, now let's move with respect to some type of, OCRs, which are directly available.
PAUL: Okay? Now, little bit with unstructured, the ideas get familiar, so I will just go to unstructured Docs.
PAUL: Yeah? Because at the end of the day, this is the place where you spend most of the time.
PAUL: Okay, remember right now.
PAUL: Okay, so… and based on here, try Unstructured for free. They do have, okay, And…
PAUL: EY with supported file types. So, right now, really, that file type that they have given, if you look into.
PAUL: Really, the list is very, very long.
PAUL: Okay, ODD, port, RST, Relative, by file type, different types, Apple, CSB, database, email, EPUB. Now, in some places, I feel that this list, which Unstructured has provided, it's more comprehensive as compared to Topi.
PAUL: This is only one thing.
PAUL: Because, really, like, I don't work with so many formats, like, Star Office. Really, I don't know who works, but somebody might be working, at least I know.
PAUL: There are others, like, really working with OpenOffice.odt, again.
PAUL: EPUB, DBASE… I hope you get it, because with respect to these file formats of this particular set, which Unstructor has, I feel that this is a little bit robust compared to Dockley. So, in my use case, I use an hybrid. It means I use both the frameworks.
PAUL: Now, going forward, the idea is that you can select, okay, for PDF, I will be using this. It's working very good. Now, similarly, for if I… if some type of dockets file comes into the picture, then probably I can move to this library. Similarly, some other type of file that comes into the picture, again, you can change. I hope you are getting my point.
PAUL: Why I am teaching you the frameworks. The idea is that don't stick to a single framework. Always think about if something is not available in that framework, try to integrate it. Okay, like a hybrid data parsing framework that you might build.
PAUL: Did you get the point?
PAUL: what is the purpose? Because, really, like, I don't work with so many file formats, but somebody might be working, that's the idea. If something is missing in Docklink, go to unstructured, because at least Unstructured might have support for that, whereas Docklink totally might not have support for that.
PAUL: Alright, now with respect to the next part. Practically, we'll be dealing with a fixed type of document, nevermudasar.
PAUL: Like, if you are building an open-end system for any type of… how can you think about it will be… the document type will always be fixed?
PAUL: It is never fixed. There will be different type of file formats, if you're actually creating any type of product or service.
PAUL: I can… if it's an internal thing, I can say that, okay, you can restrict your system by certain file types, but actually, if you're making any type of product, okay, where it can be, like, open-ended, the idea is that the user can pass any type of file.
PAUL: Hmm.
PAUL: If it is generally a restriction to a file type, it's a bad thing.
PAUL: to do it.
PAUL: Okay, now the idea is that if you… you can build a system, C, then you will be making your life easier as a developer, if you say that, okay, the whole world needs to use PDF only.
PAUL: Now, that's a restriction you can always put, but the idea is that at the end of the day, anybody can pass anything.
PAUL: Okay, the priorities are always set to first show to PDFs and others, but if somebody brings some other format, your system should be able to handle, that's the idea. If you don't want simply an error file not supported, please upload a PDF file. Those things anybody can do.
PAUL: Alright, now… okay, now this is the main part.
PAUL: Okay, now, see, with respect to different types of connectors, these, type of connectors which are available, can you see?
PAUL: Okay, now these connectors are available where? It is available in the Enterprise Edition. In the open source edition, there is nothing.
PAUL: Okay, so really, like, I'll be talking about only one LAMA path which I feel that which is widely used, but again, unstructured enterprises are also being used.
PAUL: Okay, because unstructured is a bit older as compared to Llama parts.
PAUL: So, this is also a good one. With respect to examples. So, you can always look into multiple types of examples, vector database integrations, okay, table extraction from PDF. Okay, at every point of time, you will see a very similar example that we'll be using. Okay, now, in this example, right now, even we have looked into.
PAUL: A very similar, I can say, boilerplate, where you are taking that partition underscore PDF, then you were passing. So, exactly what type of strategy. So, here they are referring to high-resolution strategy.
PAUL: Okay? And then, element-wise, right now, they are just focusing on the table.
PAUL: Okay? And based on that, they are getting the information from the table, as well as the metadata of the table.
PAUL: please let me know, okay? Because very similar, other implementations are there. You can always look into, but yes, few implementations that they have provided is much more towards the
PAUL: I can say Enterprise Edition, like Azure Blob, Amazon S3, directly. Okay, so these are directly available in their platform, which is basically the unstructured.hive.
PAUL: Now, let's get back to our discussion with respect to OCRs, as we were discussing. Let me know, should we go for a break of 10 minutes, and then should we continue?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Please add this link to Notion. I think somewhere in references, this link will come. See, in my resource section, I always add these links, whoever is asking for the links, okay? Alright.
PAUL: Alright, let's go for a break of 10 minutes, okay, and then we will continue.
PAUL: Okay, now, with respect to installation issues, like, how many of you felt that, yes, really, issues are there? Because that's why the idea was, in today's class, I built everything from scratch. Virtual environment, installing the packages.
PAUL: Please let me know, guys.
PAUL: Till now, issues are there, okay, fine. System dependency issues are there.
PAUL: Where I work with you. Any development work right now? No, Gary, we are not taking that.
PAUL: for Tesseract, add it to your Windows path, okay, and then pass that path into your environment variable, system environment variable, that is the idea.
PAUL: Just wait, let me then start the timer, I think, where is the clock?
PAUL: A 10 minutes timer, I will start, even I will do my breakfast.
PAUL: Oh, so this is… Good luck, okay? So, guys, let's be back in time.
PAUL: Alright guys, so we are back, okay? So, something.
PAUL: So, Sanjay is stating the requirement is guaranteed to break on Mac OS, okay, alright, I've already told you, remove the versions at any point of time, Sanjay. So, very specific to OS part, like, for me, this is working, but in your case, always remove the versions.
PAUL: The idea is to use the latest version, just like this time I have done it. Okay, so don't mention very specific versions that might actually break.
PAUL: Depends upon the waste.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Now, coming to a little bit with respect to layout analyzing.
PAUL: Okay, so I think, with respect to our notebook… Okay.
PAUL: Now, this is the part with respect to OCR configurations, okay, and very specifically, what type of high-resolution model that you want to use.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to your OCR configurations. So, at any point of time, you need to define the layout model. So, generally, two models, which are very famous. Okay, one is the detectron.
PAUL: If you remember in last class, I told you about layout parser, about a particular package.
PAUL: Anybody remembers about that particular package, which is from Detectron 2?
PAUL: I think… me out.
PAUL: Martha.
PAUL: Detect one.
PAUL: Boom.
PAUL: Anybody has worked with Detectron?
PAUL: to understand a particular document layout at any point of time, you can use it. But yes, again, like, the dependencies are there at any point of time when you are working with this. Okay, so right here in different type of OCR engines.
PAUL: Okay, so right now I'm using Yolo X, which is always easy to work with, as compared to Detectron 2, because Detectron 2 has a lot of dependencies.
PAUL: So, right here, if I show you very specifically, I think…
PAUL: somewhere in the documentation part, okay? So, with respect to different type of models that you have under unstructured, okay, OCR-based and transformer-based models to detect elements in the documents.
PAUL: The models are useful to detect complex layout in documents and predict the element types.
PAUL: Okay, and right here, very specifically, in this particular parameter of high resolution model name that you have, it supports two main parameters. Okay, so one is YOLOX and detect from two ONX.
PAUL: Yeah, so YOLOX, so right now that I will be using, okay, you can test it out with Detectron 2. Because Detectron 2 has a lot of dependencies, because of that, we might get some type of errors, and this is an ONIX format.
PAUL: How many of you know about ONIX format? The Open Neural Exchange format? At any point of time, you convert from PyTorch to ONIX, or from ONIX to TensorFlow, an intermediate form.
PAUL: format in the field of deep learning. Anybody has used ONIX?
PAUL: Majorly, it is used widely with respect to deployments.
PAUL: Alright, nobody has used Onyx. Fine.
PAUL: So, right now, very specifically.
PAUL: For model resolution, I am passing an OCR configuration here, and I am telling that I will be working with a model YOLO. I think everybody has heard about YOLO. You only look once.
PAUL: YOLO models, which are widely used for object detection. Okay, now this is a very specific variant which is used for layout detection.
PAUL: Okay? Now, based on this, once I have passed the OS configuration, the OCR configuration, now in the next step, partition image. Okay, then I'm basically passing the image path that we do have. Okay.
PAUL: Now, let me just take the few configurations.
PAUL: Because the part where I have executed this.
PAUL: this particular variable exactly where it is defined. Let me just try to… Look into that.
PAUL: Okay, so, right now.
PAUL: This image path, okay, this image path variable is not available, so let me just define it here for now.
PAUL: Image underscore path. I think in some previous cells, that might be available. Okay?
PAUL: Alright, so I know there is a sample image file that I have, which is sample1.png, okay, or some other file also that I can actually take it.
PAUL: Alright, now let me just try to take this particular file. I'm using a high resolution, OCR language is English, very specifically.
PAUL: D.
PAUL: So, right now, I have just performed a simple read operation. I am not printing out any information. Okay, please let me know.
PAUL: How many of you can simply print it out? Because right now, I'm just looking into the elements of the OCR that is coming. And based on that, very specifically, that I'm getting the information.
PAUL: with respect to the elements that I have. Similarly, you can change the image, so I think I do have a VDB.png.
PAUL: Okay, so a vector database, I think, VDB… okay, and let me just print out… because right now, this is within a try block, and I know that this particular file exists, OCR elements, I'm applying partition in a bench.
PAUL: Strategy high resolution, OCR language is equal to English, and then I'm finally, printing out for every element.
PAUL: Now, this question that I have, because…
PAUL: Very specifically, this is the OCR configuration that I have defined.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on this, okay, now this is a very complex image that I have given, if I really show you. Both here extracted 5 different elements. Okay, like, okay, now really, like, the spailing can be mystic, if you really look into the image.
PAUL: Okay, now, this is something like a quadrant, if you really look, step, insert data, queries, refine, maintain, monitor, okay, an entire flow-based information that I had.
PAUL: Based on this particular, flow. Really, if you, try to look into the notebook right here.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, like, G, you can see here, yes, it is failing with respect to, like, based on the elements at any point of time, then comes quadrant vector databases.
PAUL: Alright, few elements, setup, size, details, but again, I don't feel exactly the information which is coming. Okay.
PAUL: Because right now, really, can you understand exactly what are the elements? Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, because on top of images, really, there is no structure that can be defined. You have to understand this. In documents, you can have element-wise structure, but do you think on top of images, there will be element-wise structure?
PAUL: On top of images, is it possible?
PAUL: Yes or no, guys? Please let me know. On top of images, do you really think there will be some type of structure that will be maintained? Images are images.
PAUL: Okay, so really, in these type of cases, okay, really, like, it will fail or not.
PAUL: Okay, because really, for images, it's pretty much, rather than true to say, for images at any point of time, it's very, very important to take very good OCRs.
PAUL: Rather than only depending on some type of layout structure definition.
PAUL: Okay, so here I can see that, yes, some elements that have been extracted, but really, to understand the meaning of these elements, it's not so much interesting here. Okay, you can print out all the elements by taking the zeroth index, and then you can actually get the information.
PAUL: Because in images, it's all about pixel value. Yes, yeah, like, that's the core idea.
PAUL: Now?
PAUL: Let's… stake. Okay, so now this part I have not executed.
PAUL: Let's take this one.
PAUL: I will just perform an, operation, so…
PAUL: Let me just, first of all, uncomment this part.
PAUL: Okay, so scanned PDF, okay, so what I will do, I have to pass some type of path here.
PAUL: And this will be with respect to, sample…
PAUL: slash document slash scanned document. Okay, the idea is to pass some type of scanned document. I do have a scanned… okay, no, this one. Okay, scanned.pdf, let me pass this one, and let's see…
PAUL: any type of results that I'll be getting it or not.
PAUL: Okay, I'm doing changes in the function. Similarly, you guys can also do it. OCR only, multi-languages. Okay, so right now, very specifically, two languages that I'm very specifically focusing on, English plus FRE.
PAUL: So, whenever you are installing any type of OCR in your system, just be sure you have multi-language support. So, generally, for multi-language support, you need to install some other packages also. So generally, like, how many of you have installed Tesseract today?
PAUL: For Tesseract, there is, another command, basically, like, tesseract-languages, or tesseract-length, using which you can
PAUL: actually install multiple type of language support. So, similarly, for every type of OCR, okay, like Rapid OCR, easy OCR, all this type of OCR has multilingual support.
PAUL: Now, this, I cannot print it right now. Okay, so very specifically, let me just print out the elements from here.
PAUL: Okay, so, based on this… with the tank…
PAUL: Probably just, let's look into the length of the elements. So right now, I have passed one PDF strategy OCR. Okay, so let's take this, though this is not actually a scanned one, but the idea is that some type of handwritten information that I am passing.
PAUL: Could not open this file? Okay, alright. Looks like the path I have given, it is can.pdf.
PAUL: can.pdf, okay? Now let me just try to see.
PAUL: Okay, it's taking some time.
PAUL: Muthasara, please look into, like, if something is not defined, please try to define.
PAUL: Because I'm also doing the same thing. So right now, the total number of elements that are coming from the PDF is close to 52, okay? Now, really, the idea, like, if you want to look at every element, okay? So, because right now, the total number of elements…
PAUL: Holy shit.
PAUL: Okay, print the element text and something like this, I think I can do it.
PAUL: Let me try to execute this, because directly, whatever came.
PAUL: Based on that, I'm just trying to print out some information from the elements.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Okay, you guys, now, the information that is coming, really, like, you have to understand, the OCR is performing really bad, as last time, very specifically, we have used… okay, now, if you try to look into this particular document, scan.pd.
PAUL: Okay? In scan.pdf, okay, you have, like, this type. Somewhere here, person A to person C is written, okay, and if you go here, cosine, similarity, purpose, calculate the distance between vectors, okay?
PAUL: Now, here, actually, I look into the title, like, co-sign, co… really not St. Louis. I mean, I went, okay.
PAUL: Okay, now here, let me just remove French.
PAUL: I don't know, probably it might have detected something. Let's go only with English and see it this time.
PAUL: At least how it is performing. Yes, I have to change the language correctness.
PAUL: Okay, now, really, here also, based on the result.
PAUL: Okay, that I have, really. I cannot say a lot of improvement.
PAUL: Okay, because right now I've just used English language.
PAUL: But then also the results that I have. Okay, so some places here, but again, I can say that, yes, a lot of mistakes are there.
PAUL: Okay, but again, not a very robust
PAUL: I can say Oziat. Now, in these cases, what I will do?
PAUL: Please tell me, guys, in these cases, what you will do very specifically.
PAUL: When you have these type of documents, Yes?
PAUL: When you have these type of documents, how we will extract?
PAUL: information, if I'm talking with respect to any framework, because really, here, the framework doesn't matter.
PAUL: what that matters to you is, actually, you need a very good OCR. Something like, you will directly say that, okay.
PAUL: probably, like, this particular formula that I have. Okay, now for this particular formula, nobody can generate you the text. It means that somehow you need to convert it into latex, but
PAUL: These type of things can easily be detected by any, like, easy OCR can do it. Like, the idea is that you need a bounding box for this particular piece of text. Again, for this piece of text. For every piece of text, there will be a certain bounding box.
PAUL: And I know that within that bounding box, certain characters will be there. Now, based on that, the results will always be good.
PAUL: Okay, now it totally depends, because right now, the OCR, really, like, if I am talking by default, it picks up the easy OCR. Okay, but, not easy OCR, Tesseract OCR, but Tesseract is really not so much good in 2025. Right now, what is the best OCR in the market?
PAUL: Mistral OCR and Deep Sea OC OCR, they are really, really good, okay, at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, easy OCR, parallel OCR, they also work, but very specifically for these type of file tasks, okay, I will really ask you to, use a very specific OCR, do the testing, and then actually bring it to your rack pipeline.
PAUL: Yes, they are open source. Mistrial is not open source, DPOCR is open source.
PAUL: Mr. Losier is speed 1.
PAUL: Alright, now coming to the part with respect to lanchain integration, because finally, if we have done something, okay, the idea is that to integrate with any type of framework. So, similarly, integrations are there with other frameworks also. So, right now, the lanchain part, we will look into.
PAUL: What is the best OCR, Mistral OCR, and DeepSheck OCR for now, in 2025? They have really performed very, very good.
PAUL: Okay, so two ACRs in 2025, you should always check it out. Some older OCRs, that easy OCR, Paddle OCR, Rapid OCR, these things that you can test it out.
PAUL: Okay, right now, even, Hunihan OCR came. Okay, so that is also good.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, let me check with respect to a few integrations. Okay, and right now, see, if you are working directly with LangChain.
PAUL: Okay, so there is simply a loader, which is basically the unstructured loader which comes from the package of Langchen-unstructured. So this package should be installed in your
PAUL: If it is not installed, simply will get an error.
PAUL: Now, with respect to unstructured loaders, okay, now directly, I'm using this class, and I am passing the file type, okay, and based on that, I'll be getting, like, whatever the documents is there, okay, I'm just printing that. Okay, and let's look into, because now the idea is get used to a little bit of Langchen structure.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Now, here, if you look into loaded, okay, based on the documents that I have, so really, sample.html.
PAUL: Okay, document, loader.load. I'm passing the length of the document right now, length of the doc, so really, like, in this particular HTML file, if you really look into.
PAUL: the first content, okay, I'm just looking into the first content, and initially with 200 characters. I feel that, yes, the metadata that is being generated, this information is actually from unstructured, and not from Langshan. Can I say that? If you really look into the metadata.
PAUL: Even we, discuss about this, last time modified category depth, what is the English
PAUL: basically the language which has been detected, what is the file directory, file name, file type, category, element ID,
PAUL: Everything that is coming around.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Similarly, now, I will change the document, so let's, simply change it to some other PDF. I think I do have the docklink PDF here, so let me just copy the path.
PAUL: Okay, yes.
PAUL: Okay, now this is telling 296 LanChain documents. So, guys, when I'm showing you this LanChain documents.
PAUL: I hope everybody understands These documents are actually the elements.
PAUL: Don't think about, I am passing only one PDF, so how 276 documents are coming?
PAUL: That's why I showed you the elements part. Now, when you actually, do the integration of Langchain with your unstructured, then you will be getting always this particular information.
PAUL: I hope you remember this. Previously, also, when I worked with Doclinks, the number of elements for this particular document was coming to 276.
PAUL: Okay, now similarly, you can change the files, and based on that, you can always look into
PAUL: Okay, so now looking into, different… now, this is a simple print statement with different types of mood, single, elements, and page, different type of modes which are available.
PAUL: Okay, now this modes is basically where you can pass this as a parameter. Each element as a separate document, do you need that
PAUL: Because sometimes, somebody might need in such use cases. Now, based on those elements, do you feel, okay, otherwise single, the entire document as a single object type? Okay, if you feel that you need a single document, then you can pass single, then paste each page as a separate document.
PAUL: Can you see the level that it is giving, where in Langchain you cannot actually get this type of one? Digvijay is asking, are this chunked documents, where have we applied chunks?
PAUL: Have you applied any charging?
PAUL: It is the elements of unstructured, don't get confused.
PAUL: It is the elements. See, last time, also, very specifically, I told you, these are elements, if you remember last time, whenever we are working with, the same thing that here. So, by default, if you look into, okay, it's telling 276.
PAUL: It means that all the elements that are coming by default. Okay, now, I'm telling you there are different modes that do you need in a single shot? Okay, now the number of elements will decrease based on the selection that you do. So right now, 3 types of selection are there, the single, the elements, and paged. So, in this way, you can always do a manipulation.
PAUL: Okay? So, simply… Documents in single mode?
PAUL: So, right now, can you see that this number has pretty much reduced?
PAUL: Previously, what was the number?
PAUL: Yes, previously the number has reduced right now, because right now we have taken the single mood. Similarly, if I change the mode.
PAUL: Let's take, elements now, in the next one.
PAUL: Okay, so somewhere, I think, let's change… oh, let's check out all the different modes that you have.
PAUL: Now, see, this is basically the mode with the elements, where you have all the elements that you need to access, so based on that, 276,
PAUL: Now, very specifically, in the single mode, right now, you can see the number of elements had reduced. So, at any point of time, when you are using, just be sure. I feel much more that most of the time, this single document has… it is much more important.
PAUL: Okay, sometimes, like, PDF-based, very specifically, like, paged information, this also you can use it.
PAUL: We're good.
PAUL: So, let me just change this to some PDF for now.
PAUL: Okay? Because the idea is to take a PDF document, and let's get a paged version of that one. So, this particular file path, I will be using it again. Okay, so let me… because previously it was an HTML file, so really it doesn't matter what is the type, okay? That has been defined.
PAUL: Okay, so let me change the file type here. Okay, and now here, more difficult to elements.
PAUL: Okay, so I think now the number of elements that are coming is 276. Now, let me change the mode from elements to single.
PAUL: Okay, now the length will change for sure.
PAUL: Okay, so somewhere around… Elements is giving this… okay, that's why I'm thinking why this is coming again 20.
PAUL: Must… sample… Yes.
PAUL: Alright, defaulting to the first 500 characters with respect to single mode. Okay, so right now, the export type that you have… okay, so here, let me, if I pass more information, let me make it something close to 1000.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Right now, initially, the number of characters that you have. So, can I say that in this particular element, we didn't have 1,000 characters?
PAUL: Because right now, I'm just printing out the first element only, and here there are… if you change the element, so probably let's go with a different element right now. I'm not printing out all the elements, the idea is to look into very specific… now, here comes introduction. So probably, again, if I change the element, okay, somewhere you will be getting a bigger amount of text.
PAUL: So, element-wise parsing at any point of time that you can do it here. Now, similarly, for sample documents, again, I will change
PAUL: Now, see, at any point of time, so these are the parameters that you have been using, file path, mode, element, strategy.
PAUL: And by default, like, don't use high resolution. Use fast most of the times, it works very, very good. Okay, and the mood type that I am using is elements, very specifically. The idea is to access all the elements through this.
PAUL: Rather than a single time.
PAUL: Okay? Now, based on this, again, the core document that I have, 276, now the idea is to print out
PAUL: like, in the first page. Now, can you see that page-wise element access also you can get it?
PAUL: This is very, very important.
PAUL: at any point of time, this information, we can actually keep it in our metadata of a particular PDF during, like, when we are generating the chunk at that particular point of time in metadata, we can store this type of information.
PAUL: Okay, this is how you make your metadata much more vibrant at any point of time. Okay, the idea is to have more and more information. Through unstructured, I feel that if you actually go ahead with unstructured, the amount of metadata information for a particular document is much…
PAUL: Vibrant as directly comparing it with Doppling. In Doppling, I feel, metadata is good, but actually, such level of information you don't always get. Like, see, element-wise, you cannot get it there. Now, page-wise, element-wise, okay, that's an additional, really good feature of Unstructure.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is to make your metadata much better at any point of time, so you can do it. So, in this particular page number, in this particular element.
PAUL: So you get a much detailed information exactly in the document where is that particular piece of text.
PAUL: Now, working with multiple files, okay, so… at any point of time, if you're working with LanChain, what is that reader using which you can directly load multiple types of files?
PAUL: Last class, also, we discussed about directory loader. Anybody remembers about directory loader in LanChain?
PAUL: Yes, you can directly pass the directory loader, whatever the files are there, and you can read it in one shot.
PAUL: Pretty much,
PAUL: Okay, GLOB is not required in that case. With Glob also, you can do it, but with glob, you'll be specifying that, okay, I'll be only focusing on HTML files.t files. Or if you…
PAUL: Pass star, okay, it means that every type of file type that you want to look into. Okay, a very similar strategy. Right now, I am passing two different types of file types, and one by one that I am reading. Now, this approach, I don't prefer always, rather than if I'm going ahead with LangChain, and I prefer much more the directory loader.
PAUL: Okay, now looking into the core part, because few things that I have looked into. Okay, now, I will be giving you an assignment very specifically. In that assignment, you have to do some tasks with respect to multimodal part.
PAUL: Because, see, multimodal path, yesterday I discussed very specifically, but I want you guys at least to explore this.
PAUL: And why, very specifically, that at least, like, in last class, I have shown you working with audio, video, if you're… sorry, not video, images, and audio, two things.
PAUL: Okay, now this will be a very specific assignment that I'll be giving, where you need to, just for data passing, it means that if I pass you an MP3 file, okay?
PAUL: How you can do it in unstructured. If I pass you simply an image, how you can do it in unstructured?
PAUL: Please let me know, can you guys do it? You just need to refer to the documentation, and based on that, you need to pick up exactly, like, what is the partition that you need.
PAUL: At any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, and really, with respect to when you'll be going with multimodal, okay, really, I feel that Dockling is better, so even that's why I've not kept that particular part here. But the idea is to explore. So, in your notion, I'll be keeping it as an assignment. Very specifically, working with MP3 files.
PAUL: or .wav files, okay? And directly passing some type of PNG, JPG, those type of file formats.
PAUL: Now, let's take the example by integrating it. See, whenever I'm doing any integration, okay, so what is the thing that I am changing?
PAUL: Okay, I will be writing all things about the assignment in Notion, don't worry. Right now, just focus on the, main rack pipeline that we are discussing.
PAUL: Yes, so right now, if you really look here, only one import, I don't know, because Lanshan.tech splitters, actually, we don't use it, we use lanchan underscore. I don't know how it is working, but Lanshan underscore tech splitter is not working in my system.
PAUL: Okay, so the actual import should be like this.
PAUL: Okay, that I feel.
PAUL: Because this is the new syntax, because language and text splitter is a separate package. Okay, but when I mention something like this, I feel that, okay, now this is a problem. This used to be done previously.
PAUL: Okay, so check, like, in your system, which input is working. Like, with the underscore or with the dot.
PAUL: Because, I feel that, yes, in this part.
PAUL: there can be some type of issues with respect to Langshan.text splitter is working.
PAUL: With dot, it is working, with underscore, Pashant is telling it's working, alright? Because, I feel that the LangChain version that I do have in my system, okay, so let's try to do the analyze of that also. Sometimes it might happen with that picture.
PAUL: Blank chain.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the command.
PAUL: Okay, can you see here? The specific version that came around is 0.3.27. So, probably, I think, if you are in one
PAUL: anything, like, 1.5… okay, 1.05, 1.06, probably in that case. Probably I need to upgrade my lan chain. This is one idea, okay? So, like, if I try to upgrade my lan chain here.
PAUL: I won't… Okay, I will do a PIP,
PAUL: First of all, let me just do an uninstall of the current version of LanChain.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And in the next step, I will be doing an UV uninstall.
PAUL: Mmm…
PAUL: I think it's about the Python version. Yes, I'm using a Python version, but see, really, because… now, this is where, generally, you take in an upgrade, because I know that this import is wrong, but right now, I don't know, like, exactly. It is working in my system. Okay, so…
PAUL: The idea is that later on, at least upgrade Langchain. That's for everyone. I think everybody is in LanChain 105, or 106, 107, those versions. Anybody who's in 0.3.27?
PAUL: Okay, if in 3.13.9, okay, there can be. Alright, fine. My… I think my Python version is 3.12.9 that I am using.
PAUL: Alright, but always remember that this is not the latest package, okay? It's now working fine, because really, like, underscore is not getting detected, though my Langchen TechSplitter package is of the latest version that we do have.
PAUL: Now, this part is done, okay. Now the next step is basically loading different type of documents.
PAUL: Okay, now this is a simple function that we have, and inside this function, right now, all underscore dots, a blank list in which I'll be appending the information. Okay, then, simply, I have a simple for loop. Within that for loop, the idea is that loop for the files.
PAUL: and then pass it to your unstructured loader. And then, one by one, the file path, which is basically right now, within the loop.
PAUL: Okay, the iterator. Okay, so one by one, it will do the iteration of the file path, and based on that, it will be loading. And right now, the mode that I am passing is basically get individual elements, strategy fast that I have taken.
PAUL: Okay, so once this is done, finally, I'll be loading the docu… Loading each of the documents, okay, into docs, and then finally, I am extending them.
PAUL: I hope everybody understood the meaning of extend and append.
PAUL: in list, Python list, pretty common concept, which is widely used. Okay. Now, based on this, so two files that I am passing. So, let me just pass a little bit more files.
PAUL: It's really… okay, now, I've really increased,
PAUL: complexity, little bit, I think, okay, because really, I've really passed
PAUL: Okay, a lot of files. Let me see what happens. I've added PDF, Docs, XLS, PPTX, everything.
PAUL: Okay, all types of file types. Okay, now let me run this one.
PAUL: Okay, now the total number of documents which are loaded is, right, 151. Now, when I'm talking about total docs.
PAUL: So, what do I refer to, docs?
PAUL: elements.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, you need to do a calculation of loaded 20 elements from this document. Loaded 44 elements from this document.
PAUL: Okay, and my strategy was very specifically with respect to elements, get individual elements.
PAUL: Each and every file needs to be added SR, even if…
PAUL: One lag. Each and every file needs to be added.
PAUL: Generally, like, each file is not added, you can create your own, like, if you feel that all the files are available within that folder, okay, you can use something like directory loader, or something like that. The core part is getting all our paths, so now this is hard-coded, you can make it automated through Path, Globe, there are a lot of packages powered.
PAUL: Okay, now, here, very specifically, I'm using the recursive character text splitter. Now, this is where my code might break, okay, because of the text splitter import package issue, but let me see whether it works or not.
PAUL: So, right now, what are the things? So, this is the initialization of the recursive character text splitter. Okay, then, based on that, I will be passing the list of documents that I have.
PAUL: So, very specifically, this is the variable, okay, where all the information is there. Now, this variable I am passing in the next step, let's focus on…
PAUL: Fewer, okay, one of the chunks.
PAUL: So right now, documents after splitting, okay, so again, 145 that I have, right now, the channel size is close to 550. And really, based on the documents that I have, I feel that, yes.
PAUL: right now, the total documents loaded is 151. Now, see, you have to analyze from here. 151 actually was there. Now, it has become 155. So, can I say that some document was towards the bigger side? Because, see, most of the document will come under this 500 characters.
PAUL: Because all the sample documents that I have, every one is small. Sample.html, this one is at least bigger that I feel. Other than that, sample.md, this is. Whereas sample.pdf, sample.xls, sample.pptx, sample.doc, these are all very small files.
PAUL: Okay, because of that, right now, the length of the chunk that you are actually looking into, okay, now that has increased. So, length of split top. So, this is your final chunks that you have.
PAUL: Okay, and very specifically, like, focusing on the first one. Okay, so let me just look into the other one also.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, source, sample, HTML, and right now, this is the content with respect to the overview. So, really, even if I pass it here, 400,
PAUL: Okay, so let me just show you.
PAUL: Okay, so here… Based on the chunk, some content is there with respect to document parsing.
PAUL: Okay? And can you see that within, that this, actually, the metadata is also coming? Now, this is really great. For metadata generation, I feel unstructured is better as compared to docklings.
PAUL: Alright, fine, so simply, I have added two things.
PAUL: it will not join the elements, all the elements will be separate. If you feel that within an element, there is a lot amount of text, now, based on the chunking strategy, that document will only be broken.
PAUL: Elements only be… so, within an element, you should have a lot of information, then that element will be broken into two chunks, or three chunks.
PAUL: I hope you get it.
PAUL: Okay, if the element is only small, it means that under 500 characters you have, based on this chunk size ratio. So, really, there won't be any type of issues. And in our documents, we know, in few documents, the amount of information was towards the hard side, okay?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, this I have already printed, now let's focus on creating embeddings.
PAUL: Okay, fine. I am using Chroma, so I think there won't be any type of problem. Okay, so here, the vector DB initialization. I think everybody is familiar with this one. There is nothing new.
PAUL: And you people have already looked into Chroma, Quadrant, Viviat, very similar structure.
PAUL: Okay, and now let me just pass it.
PAUL: Okay, it will just take some time.
PAUL: one new folder, ChromaDB Unstructured Folder, this will also be created.
PAUL: I hope nobody is getting the issue of kernel crash or something like that.
PAUL: Please let me know anybody is facing that issue of kernel crash.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Lib magic is unavailable, but assigning into file type detection. This is a warning.
PAUL: Rahul.
PAUL: It's not an error. And lib magic, I think it needs to be installed in OS level.
PAUL: I have added in the PDF here, it's working fine.
PAUL: Okay, Raja, the dockling. Okay.
PAUL: All right, in my case, really.
PAUL: Based on the time it is taking, so let's see.
PAUL: Okay, some type of value error that came, and this error is coming from, okay, the HTTP request.
PAUL: Alright, try filtering complex metadata. Okay, alright, alright, alright. Last time, I have updated it, this is fine.
PAUL: Okay, alright, I will take this import.
PAUL: Okay, so in last class, we have already done it in docklinks, if you remember.
PAUL: Anybody remembers, very specifically?
PAUL: Okay, because, right now the format that we do have, so this part I need to change from…
PAUL: Language and community vector store, import, filter, metadata, complex, okay? Now, that needs to be called here, on top of docklinks.
PAUL: Cool.
PAUL: So generally, once you are passing the split documents, okay, so before this, the idea is to initialize this.
PAUL: So, like, late underscore talks… physical, too.
PAUL: Builder…
PAUL: Now, based on the keys, okay. So, last time also, we have done a very similar implementation, okay, because…
PAUL: The chain is a little bit different this time, okay? So, I will just do a quick verification, because I remember, yes, this was there in the RAG pipeline.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to the rag part.
PAUL: Before invoking the chain, I passed it there. Okay? So, directly, I passed the documents, rather than very specifically, okay? So, let me take this one.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just, remove…
PAUL: Okay, I think, for now, I don't need this one.
PAUL: Put in hash, and then hash.
PAUL: Okay, and the actual information was split underscore talks.
PAUL: Please check, now it is working or not.
PAUL: Yeah, so these two lines are in hash mode, it's fine.
PAUL: So, now let me see.
PAUL: Is it working now?
PAUL: Okay? So, always, when you get a value error, just always look into what is the error, because most of you…
PAUL: when you actually try to debug, because, see, I know the error when I look into the function. The idea is that you guys also used to one framework very good.
PAUL: Okay, because right now, as the focus is much more towards land chain, okay, so very specifically, like, just try to be good in that. At any point of time you get an error, okay, directly you can look into. Because many of you directly pasted it, but if you remember the same thing, we have done it in the last class.
PAUL: So, from there, I remembered it.
PAUL: Alright. Now, people with name error, just define it, as simple as that. Okay.
PAUL: I have done it in front of you right now.
PAUL: Okay, so it's pretty much…
PAUL: Simple. Just the ideas, remember, exactly. Now, based on this, okay, the idea is to initialize the retriever, and based on that, I'm asking a simple question, what is document parsing?
PAUL: Now, do you think that I do have any relevant documents with respect to document parsing?
PAUL: Okay, so let's try to look at least, okay, and based on that, let me just print out some more characters.
PAUL: But really, I don't think I… do I have that?
PAUL: Okay, there is some information in that sample.html file with respect to document parsing. Based on that, I'm getting the top 3 relevant chunks. The other one is also from sample.html, where the term document parser is coming. Okay, I can say that.
PAUL: Similarly, in your sample.markdown file, again, as a document parsing best practices.
PAUL: So, yes, okay, so 3 different types of, information that I had.
PAUL: What is the recent code change that anybody needs? Please let me know in the chat. Rahul, like…
PAUL: The code is same, I just fixed it now.
PAUL: So exactly which part you are asking, please do let me know.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now in the next step, if, the initialization, if vector store is available, and we know our vector store is available here, okay?
PAUL: So… right now… okay, so once let me complete the rack chain, then I will push the new code.
PAUL: Okay, so vector store initialization with respect to our query. Okay, the results, this part is done.
PAUL: Now, let's try to initialize the chain.
PAUL: Okay, so retrieval Q&A, font chain type, if vector store, okay, if OS, so both the value should be true, then I'm passing my LLM definition, then my retriever.com into the picture, and then finally my chain initialization.
PAUL: Okay, so two things that comes…
PAUL: Okay, and let me see whether… because right now it's just the definition, it might feel here. Okay, the rack chain got created successfully. Now, once the rack chain is done, the idea is to pass a question to the particular chain that I have defined.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, the chain… the idea is to invoke the chain and pass that within the query. So based on that question, so this part is pretty much just, like, our last classes that we have done it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: let's see, very specifically, because right now, based on the query, first embeddings will be created, and based on that, yes, I am getting the answer, and the sources majorly that has been used is sample.md, sample.html, sample.htmd, okay, now these are the core source files.
PAUL: She is right now, directly not using LCL.
PAUL: Using a retry bulging. The same thing, same implementation.
PAUL: Yes, like, every class, I'm not using LCL. Sometimes I change that format. You can use LCL, there is no restriction in using LCL. You can create a chain, just like, in this way, from chain type. So, this is also good.
PAUL: But I feel that, this is a little bit deprecated, okay, because all the chains are right now deprecated in the newer versions. They have all been moved in the Langshan Classic package, okay? So, new support will come from the chain, so really it doesn't matter. I feel that after 2 to 3 months, some syntactical change will be there.
PAUL: Okay? Alright. Now, yes, based on that, I am getting the response. So, yes, I can say that this part is working fine. Please let me know how many you are getting, the final response.
PAUL: for everyone.
PAUL: Because once I have executed this, then probably I can, move to the next part.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this piece of code that I have, okay, I'm just pushing it for now. Actually, based on the changes, let me just open my…
PAUL: GitHub, desktop.
PAUL: Okay, only the changes with respect to arm structure.
PAUL: Where is my GitHub desktop? Alright, yes.
PAUL: Let me just open new document parsers rack.
PAUL: 15… sample one…
PAUL: Unstructured, documents, line changes. Alright, so I'm pushing it.
PAUL: Okay, please do take a git pull of this one.
PAUL: Okay, I pushed it.
PAUL: everybody can take a pull based on the recent changes that I have done. It was only a single line of change if you're actually looking to.
PAUL: Now, similarly, like, few, simple reusable demos, okay, that I have kept it.
PAUL: So, similarly, it's the same thing, I am invoking the chain at the end of the day with a very specific query.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, this is the actual function, okay, and in this particular function, I'm passing that this is the RAC query. What are the applications of document passing in RAC system? A simple function, because generally these type of functions will be widely using when we'll be doing the integration with respect to fast APIs.
PAUL: Okay, and few error handling errors that I have kept it very specifically, you should always look for whenever you are working with unstructured or any other. Error handling is the most important thing. You should effectively handle it with lobby, because I feel that,
PAUL: There are very specific things that you need to handle very specific to a particular framework or a library. So, for this, I've given a simple example, okay? So, like, there can be a lot of issues with respect to file not found, permission error, or some other exception that you might get it, okay? So, based on that, you can always perform different type of filing. Now, this is a simple
PAUL: Thing that I provided. Now, right now, if you look into such files, okay, so it becomes much easier. But again, it's a good practice, everybody is working it in the production. I know that, so the idea is that you should also implement it in your way at any point of time, if you're working with Lang Chen and
PAUL: unstructured. So, based on that, few simple things that I have kept it, it's pretty much simple. File handling for document processing.
PAUL: Alright, guys, please let me know.
PAUL: for everybody, everything is working, or anybody is stuck into installation issues till now. Is there anyone?
PAUL: Because it seems just like brother of dockling, sister of dockling, that's the main thing.
PAUL: Okay. Now, open source stuff, I have already discussed, like, the idea is.
PAUL: Llama parts. Next, I'll be talking with respect to Llama parts. So,
PAUL: please let me know with respect to integration of Llama Pass. Like, you can do the installation of Llama Pass.
PAUL: Already, I provided it in the requirement.txt.
PAUL: Okay, so that also you can do, because the idea is that at least before the next class, you should be doing all the installations with respect to LAMA, at least. So these are all the packages that should be there in your system.
PAUL: Okay, so please, do the installation, that is the idea.
PAUL: Okay, should I go ahead with the installation of… in my system, or should I wait for others? Like, 5 minutes, solve the issues? Okay, should I wait for 5 minutes?
PAUL: Because, see, all these packages I will be installing in my system for Llama parts. Because next I'll be starting with at least the LlamaPass module.
PAUL: Okay, so should I wait 2 to 3 minutes? Others, please go through the notebook at least in once. Okay, that is the bare minimum.
PAUL: Okay, Rajat, during the doubt part, you can ask to me. Lama, next week? No, at least, let's start, we have time. It's not like that. If something is done, at least the installation part, it might take time for you, so at least do the basic.
PAUL: set up, so that the cells are working. In the meantime, even, I have to push the initial notebook
PAUL: Because you guys don't have access to LamaPass, I don't think I have pushed the…
PAUL: one with respect to, Lama parts till now.
PAUL: Okay, but the idea is that at least install the packages, because the same thing that I will be doing.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, with respect to Llama parts, I will just go into the documentation once.
PAUL: Mmm, just wait.
PAUL: Hmm.
PAUL: dock parser SRAG, okay, so…
PAUL: I'm just looking into exactly my file type, I have to do a copy-paste here.
PAUL: Okay, in the meantime, I'm preparing the notebook, okay, that I'll be pushing.
PAUL: Okay, because for LlamaPass, you need to create your APIs also.
PAUL: Okay, so that part I'll be talking about.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Now, I'll be pushing the file, okay, in GitHub, I think it is ready. Okay, let me do the push. Okay, Llama pass, added.
PAUL: Okay, Llama parts added, fine.
PAUL: Please check, okay, now in GitHub, you'll be having the notebook with respect to Llama parse also.
PAUL: So, for LamaPass, what are the things that you need to do? First of all, you need to
PAUL: Go to Llama Park's website.
PAUL: And you need to get your, API key.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, directly, like, Llama Index also, you can write it here. The idea is to sign up.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see, sign up option is there. So simply, like, log in or sign up, anything that you can do here.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: No, you don't need to remove any versions.
PAUL: Versions are, not required.
PAUL: So, everybody, please do the setup. I'm giving you 3 to 4 minutes. Okay, please have it checked.
PAUL: If you are getting an unauthorized error, probably it can be with respect to keys.
PAUL: Now, can you see here, very specifically, the information?
PAUL: Okay, so right now, there are a lot of features in the Llama Cloud.
PAUL: But we are much more focused towards this paths, very specifically. There are other things like extract, sheets, okay, index, classify.
PAUL: In our case, it will be much more towards the path seg, the Lama path that we have.
PAUL: So, from here, the idea is, you will, guys, you'll be using the API keys. So, please generate your API key and paste it in your .env file for everyone. Please do generate your API key, okay, and paste it in your .env file.
PAUL: I think everybody can do that. Please let me know in the chat by creating the API key.
PAUL: Okay, so simply search in Google Llama Index, okay, then do a sign-up, as simple as that. The search Llama Index.
PAUL: Okay, once you get, you will get the official website. From there, simply do a sign-up operation, okay? Once you have done the sign-up, sign in with Google, and then please create your API key. I'm giving you 2 to 3 minutes, please do that.
PAUL: Muted.
PAUL: Just write in Google.
PAUL: llama-index, the first search result that you will be getting, okay, it will be with respect to llamaindex only. So, it will be llamaindex.ai.
PAUL: Everybody, please do it.
PAUL: Then the next step, once you guys have the API key, let me know, then I will start with the installation part.
PAUL: Because at least, like, if I can discuss even the 5%, the rest I can discuss next week, I have no issues. But at least the setup should be ready so that you guys don't get stuck with installation issues, at least.
PAUL: Amar Srinivas is asking, what is API key name? I think I have shared a file with you guys, which is .env.example. Please let me know.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: env.example, here, everything is written. Please do look into the report that I have provided.
PAUL: We can copy a form, rack project if not found.
PAUL: like, RAG project, we have not worked in Project Abhijit, so… really.
PAUL: API key generated, please paste it for now.
PAUL: In the previous one. Okay, in the previous one, yes, you can do it.
PAUL: Please let me know. Many people are not responding, so I want everyone that are you on the same track?
PAUL: everybody created the API key, added it.
PAUL: Quotient 12, why we are going for Llama Cloud?
PAUL: It's just another parsing mechanism, and really, in industry, a lot of people are actually using it. That's why.
PAUL: Just a parser, nothing more.
PAUL: But this is a paid one. That's why. Everybody will be having limited limits.
PAUL: Okay, so if I try to look into the Lama Index limits, I think it's 1000…
PAUL: Something like that. Llama Pars…
PAUL: pricing. If you actually go to this section.
PAUL: somewhere with respect to pricing, if I look into.
PAUL: Okay, offers a free trial, can you see? 1,000 pages per day, or 7,000 per week.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Everyone?
PAUL: So, generally, it comes under the free tab, and after that, it will be pretty much… with respect to pricing, you can actually look into different type of pricing models that it has.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, in the Enterprise version, there are, again, a lot of integrations, very specifically.
PAUL: But, right now, people are using.
PAUL: And initially, when you sign up, you'll get a lot of credits, which will help you to do your initial task. There won't be any type of problem. It's just another variant, but completely cloud-hosted, so it's widely used in industry. It's not…
PAUL: In some cases, I feel that Doppling is better, in some cases, Llama Parse is better. That's why it totally depends upon the type of document. I cannot really say. In some cases, unstructured works really good.
PAUL: So the idea is that you guys should be able to build a hybrid parsing
PAUL: I can say system, where you might use Dockling also for one type of file type, you might use unstructured also, you might use Llama Parse also.
PAUL: to build something hybrid, hybrid passes. I hope you get my point.
PAUL: Menstrual OCR is 8-1.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: But here, it's not an… this is not an OCR that we are doing. It's much more of a parser.
PAUL: I'm able to pull my keys. Everyone with the keys, please let me know.
PAUL: Then at least we can start with the installation part.
PAUL: Okay, most of you are telling Ready, ready, ready.
PAUL: Abhis, you're saying, do Llama Parser store their data? Nobody stores, okay? It's a compliant issue, so nobody stores the data.
PAUL: But they have the option, as simple as that.
PAUL: In public, nobody will say that I store your data.
PAUL: Are there ulama-based parsers? No.
PAUL: Nothing, with respect to OLAMA. In OLAMA, what you can do, very specifically, people who are asking with respect to OLAMA, okay, few OCR models are there that you can actually use.
PAUL: Please share the URL, go to llamaindex.ai, click on the sign up option or the login option, as simple as that.
PAUL: whoever is asking, please share the URL. Just at least type, it's not only direct copy-paste, guys. Please type, at least in chat, my index. Just type this stuff, it will come, click on sign up, done, and create.
PAUL: Okay, so let's proceed ahead with the installation part. So, majorly, the packages that I require, I already kept it in requirement.txt, so I'll be pulling them from requirement, okay? So, now this is the part.
PAUL: So, let's start with, first of all.
PAUL: Let me get it from my…
PAUL: Code, okay, so here, very specifically, so these are few of the things that I need.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just copy this.
PAUL: In one shot, I will try to do it, okay? So…
PAUL: Let me just open the text editor and make everything in a single line.
PAUL: Even in the notebook, you will get that, okay? Or otherwise, directly, you can do it.
PAUL: So, llama pass… Cloud services…
PAUL: Okay, now, Llama Index is just like, Langchain, I feel, where for everything you have a separate package, even for OpenAI also.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, everything I'm converting it into a single line. The idea is to paste all the packages in one shot.
PAUL: In the terminal.
PAUL: Okay, fine.
PAUL: For Pry Project 2ML, it is good, but right now, let me just paste it here. UV.
PAUL: Then pip.
PAUL: Install.
PAUL: the entire list of packages that I require.
PAUL: Yes, everything got installed.
PAUL: Okay, now for a quick check, I will go back.
PAUL: My Lama index right now, the version is 09.48. Okay.
PAUL: Very specifically, and LlamaPass version is 0.6.88.
PAUL: Okay, so if I go here, and if I check right now, PYPI, Llama Park, what is the current version?
PAUL: That they are using.
PAUL: 0.688.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, I am using the latest version right now.
PAUL: What, and should I paste it in the Notion?
PAUL: Yes, the packages are available. Please take it from requirement.txt.
PAUL: Easily all the packages that we do have, you can simply do it.
PAUL: Okay, I've very specifically mentioned it here. Or you can use pip install hyphen r requirement.txt, that is also fine, I have no issues in that.
PAUL: Okay, so in whichever way you want to do it, please proceed ahead. The idea is that at least when I start, working, I think, let me just save it.
PAUL: I will just open my… Fine, save it, okay, Llama parse, document parser.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is to look into imports, so here, very specifically, see, in the notebook, I was using, the idea is not to always use letter versions. Okay, so here, I have just given a little bit older version. It's not very old, also. If you check somewhere around 7.7, how…
PAUL: Much time it's coming. It's around October 30, okay? So, not very, very old also. So this version also that you can test it out, okay, or stick to the latest version. In latest version, there can be some type of issues with respect to integrations that we might face.
PAUL: Alright, so guys, then I will check, first of all, with respect to the import section. So, you can do it from the notebook, from the terminal, anyhow, the idea is that the package should be up and working.
PAUL: Alright, so… right here.
PAUL: Okay, the Llama API key has been loaded here.
PAUL: Okay, and let me see that this is working fine or not. Okay, so I think Nest, I think you… it was there in my requirements, but I have not installed it.
PAUL: Okay, so few packages, yes.
PAUL: Again, for this UVP, install…
PAUL: Okay, it is already… looks like it comes pre-installed.
PAUL: Now I will just try to do an import, everybody. Please try to check the import section is working fine, because this is the major import. If this fails, it means that we have to do something else.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, I'm getting a very specific error from LAMAI index score LLMs.
PAUL: Okay, alright, fine. The idea is to debug at the end of the day. Yes, these problems are there. Okay, now I feel this issue is coming from Lama Cloud Services, okay? Now, I will just try to commend this, a very similar input is there.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, this is the part where I feel that, should I do a downgrade operation or not?
PAUL: Alright, let me try to do a download. That's why I thought about at least, let's solve the installation issues if somebody is facing. For how many of you it is working fine, please let me know.
PAUL: Please let me know, for how many of you, it is working fine.
PAUL: Okay, and see, the main core package that is creating this issue is LAMAI index score, okay? So, this is the main package. I will just check my Llama Index version. Okay, so UVPIP list.
PAUL: to this part.
PAUL: Okay, my Llama Index version that I have is 0.9.48, okay? Now, let's quickly go here.
PAUL: PYPI, Llama Index.
PAUL: Okay, the idea… okay, now can you see here, what is the version?
PAUL: See, guys, always look into here, do you feel that this version and this version is matching?
PAUL: Okay, this is the Llama Index.
PAUL: The actual one, which is 0.14.10. Okay, the main Llama Index version. Okay, and here, it's 09.4H, so probably I need to upgrade, because if I look into Llama Index score version is correct.
PAUL: Okay, so nothing, so I will just do a piv install hyphen U, and then the name of the package, which is Lama Index.
PAUL: So always try to debug in this way, exactly which package is plating the issue. Okay, now see, I've updated it, okay? Now I will just go back here.
PAUL: I will just try to do a restart of the kernel.
PAUL: Okay, now… Quickly, let me… Setup, okay, let me see now whether it's working or not.
PAUL: Now, this is coming again after the restart also.
PAUL: Now, it is coming, okay, alright?
PAUL: Yes, like, you need to really check. I'm using the latest version, so there can be some type of issues.
PAUL: Okay, so the main import that is failing here is this one.
PAUL: Too sweet.
PAUL: Let me check this one also.
PAUL: both the errors, and actually it is getting stuck at LanChain, Llama Index 4, okay? So, probably a downgrading that I will do here.
PAUL: Because really, like, even I don't know, I have to spend a lot of time just fixing these type of issues.
PAUL: Even when I create content for you, the same problem I face is. Okay?
PAUL: Now, probably, should I do a downgrade? That is the ultimate.
PAUL: Because if I am doing a downgrading operation, then I have to do it, okay? So…
PAUL: What I will do, okay, so let me just do…
PAUL: Okay, so based on the packages, Llama Index…
PAUL: Lama Parse, because Llama Parse is fine, there is no issue with Lama Parse. Llama Index is actually creating the issue.
PAUL: Let me just go with a little bit older version. Let me check whether it works or not.
PAUL: Because this is really a little bit trials that I have to do before finally deciding what to pick up.
PAUL: uninstall… Llama… index… Okay, so this is 14.10.
PAUL: Okay, let me just index score also.
PAUL: Okay, so both the things, the idea is that there is a dependency.
PAUL: I hope everybody can see. Sir, video, please. Okay, alright, with respect to video, sorry.
PAUL: Alright, so right now, see, I will be picking up a little bit, newer version. UVP… UVP install.
PAUL: just be sure, because Llama Index, installations, it really sometimes, even I feel.
PAUL: that it takes a little bit of time as compared directly with LanChain. Okay, I'm using 14.8 this time. Similarly, for Llama Index score also, let me just copy this.
PAUL: Okay, llamaindex hyphen core.
PAUL: I feel that for Core also, there is a package, okay? Now, let me just open my Python directly.
PAUL: And I will try to take this particular import where it was failing, okay?
PAUL: Then, finally, if not getting resolved, then I'll finally look into GitHub issues.
PAUL: Okay, so it's telling that till now, this is not getting solved.
PAUL: Okay, here's the notebook. I think the notebook is pushed, everybody has the access to the notebook, please let me know.
PAUL: Okay? Now, I will just try to look into, based on the error that we do have.
PAUL: Okay, so chat message cannot be found. Okay, so there is one issue. Previously, I've opened it also.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on this… Incorrect file path, okay, alright, incorrect sources.
PAUL: Okay, now, it's telling that use this particular example, okay, few example that has been provided, but directly there is no…
PAUL: A fixed one, okay, paper installed.
PAUL: I'll see… So many things that they are telling, actually, to do.
PAUL: Now call Lama Core, importVectorStore.
PAUL: Okay, I did that, and it worked for me, alright, fine, it is working fine.
PAUL: Downgrading, yes, the idea is that, like, how much should I downgrade? That is the other thing.
PAUL: Okay, now, this is actually that needs to be checked at any point of time, so these are all the major imports of Llama Index through Core that we are calling it.
PAUL: Yes, see, the steps that you might have followed, okay, it might work for you, because the process of troubleshooting is exactly the same. Okay, I know you follow my steps, and it is working for you, it's great, but for me, I feel that somewhere, okay, there can be an issue.
PAUL: Because this…
PAUL: Because I know that I will be getting that chat error issue, okay, after input.
PAUL: Alright, now this part is working fine.
PAUL: Really.
PAUL: Please check, because, see, I have not done any changes.
PAUL: But, really, the part with respect to this, I feel that after downgrading. So, really. But here, actually, when I passed here Python.
PAUL: But why it is not working here? It should actually… okay, it means that the core module has been changed, that is fine.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, everybody, please check, because, see, the steps are pretty much the same that I have done. So, for everybody, it is working, or till now, anybody is stuck at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, now, if I just try to comment this line, and I will try to comment this line, okay? Little bit. From Llama Parse, import LlamaPars.
PAUL: Well, let me see… both the imports are now working, so I can say that, yes.
PAUL: Please check, everyone.
PAUL: Installation cell is running for 5 minutes.
PAUL: Okay, wait. Because if you're doing the installation from cell, that's nothing that we can do. Yeah, you need to wait. For how many of you it is working, please let me know. At least the basic setup, okay, both are working. Everybody…
PAUL: Okay, able to fix the issue using RAPI, alright, fine, Satish. However you fix it, the core idea is
PAUL: Running for more than 7 minutes, really, like, that's why I don't prefer always to do the installation from Jupyter Notebook.
PAUL: Because in terminal, you actually get out the issues. Okay? So the idea is for many operators working. And I have already told you the process to debug. So I think you guys
PAUL: can do the debug. It means that the idea is, if you're using some latest version, try to downgrade it to at least 2 to 3 versions before. That's the only thing that I have done for now.
PAUL: Okay, so let's start our discussion a little bit with respect to Llama parts. Okay, now very specifically, let's look into the website.
PAUL: Okay, so in their product, so, like LamaPars, transform any messy documents into AI-ready data at scale. Okay, now, this is what they claim, and really, the results that comes around, okay, so it's really good, I can say.
PAUL: In a structured way. Okay, layout aware. Can you see that it takes care of the layout. Multimodal parsing is also available, granular level control at any point of time. Okay, like, you can use, better models which Llama supports.
PAUL: Okay, and most of the models are based on Llama. Okay, so that's why, majorly, all the models that you will be using are based on, not open sourced by Llama. Basically, Llama also has an OCR, but again, they are not open-sourced any stuff.
PAUL: Scalable, multilingual support, enterprise ready, pretty much few of the features that we have, okay? So now, based on that, let's try.
PAUL: Llama Parcel is widely used in production, everybody. For everybody, I'm telling you. Okay, like, one of the most successful parcels for now, I can say, in 2025. Many organizations are adopting, it makes your life much easier.
PAUL: So, first of all, let's set up a few directory, so that's why, few simple things that I have kept it, okay? So, just execute the cell.
PAUL: And then you will look into that, okay? So right now, what are the different types of file types that I have? So, only the things that I'm looking here. Nothing related to Llama parts.
PAUL: Llama Cloud and Llama Parse. Llama Parse is a service of the Lama Cloud, JANICA.
PAUL: How many of you, really? Like, this is a cloud service, the thing that I'm using, LlamaPass, how many of you are getting? Llama Parse is not open source?
PAUL: I hope for everybody it is clear, this is a proprietary service.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Because this is pretty much standard, so…
PAUL: In cloud, there are a lot of services. If you actually go into the product section, you can see X right now. We are highly focused on the parts part right now.
PAUL: Alright. Now, based on this.
PAUL: Okay, now, let's get a paper. So, here I am just downloading a research paper from the internet, which is basically the paper, attention is all you need. As simple as that. Okay, so in the sample documents, you will be getting this paper once you execute this piece of SIM.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: for everybody, I think this…
PAUL: should work, because it's direct URL lib package that I am using to download one.
PAUL: Okay, because Llama Index, what is the difference? Those are different services used for different type of file formats.
PAUL: Hmm, Melan, can you please take this next week? Alright, fine. Most people are telling Procedure it for next week.
PAUL: Then we will discuss it next week only. I have no issues, okay. Let's then proceed ahead. I hope for everybody the installation is done, see? That's why I've done the installation in front of you. Okay, just showing you that entire process. Okay, we will start the discussion of Llama parts in the next class. Okay, that is fine, but at least see.
PAUL: Because after Llama Parse, only one Vectorize is there. Again, Vectorize is pretty much small. There, also, I'll be talking about Iris much more, which are very, very specific parsing service. Okay, but the idea is that at least, see, by Saturday, before Saturday, please solve your installation issues.
PAUL: If anything is there, Okay, because…
PAUL: I don't want that at least you guys get frustrated just because of installation. You just need to be calm, and you need to check whether this is working or this is working. Okay, so just be calm.
PAUL: Alright, Lama Index, then we will start next week. Okay, so don't worry, fine.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, sometimes it's good to… sometimes it's good to complete the class a bit quick. Always stretching, I can understand. And my… I always do stretch or more, okay? It's fine.
PAUL: Now, I have just sent the Jupyter Notebook, Naga, I am using just Jupyter Notebook only. Alright, it's fine, it's totally fine. Okay, you guys guys, you guys can drop, no more teaching, okay? So, simply, if anybody has questions, they can stay here. People with respect to doubts, installation stuff, okay, whatever this, okay, they can simply stick.
PAUL: Alright, now, for, like, people with respect to installation issues. Whoever told? Okay, Rajat, okay, are you there, Rajat, with installation issues?
PAUL: Mitesh, okay, then, all installation issues, guys, please let me know.
PAUL: No, no, no, no class on Thursday. I think it's just one class was there in Thursday.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: anybody, like, I don't know that it's only that no Thursday class.
PAUL: Okay, no Thursday, don't get confused. We will be meeting next Saturday. Is it part clear?
PAUL: Okay, and one request, everybody, please create your AWS accounts also, because I don't know, probably next week.
PAUL: And probably in Sunday only, I think, because Saturday, Llama Pars, that we'll be discussing, and Vectorize is there. But after that, we will be start working on the first project. The first project, the basic Q&A, where a lot of configurations are required. So, I want you guys to be familiar, at least, with a little bit of GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, because I'll be working with GitHub Actions. I know most of you are already familiar, but few people are there who might not be familiar.
PAUL: Okay, because when I'm deploying a stuff, my focus will be much more, okay, towards the application part, rather than teaching you DevOps. You have to understand.
PAUL: I won't be teaching you the DevOps, like, exactly. Now, I will be picking up very specific tools, and based on that, I will be using the tools. Now, my toolset can be different, your toolset can be different, okay? So, just be sure you are creating your AWS accounts.
PAUL: Just get it connected, like, for India, I think UPI is also there. Okay, or just add a debit card or a credit card, just be sure. Most of the things I'll be working with, free time.
PAUL: But in some cases, probably I might need to use a… Paid tire also.
PAUL: Okay? I will upload the assignment in your Notion, in that data parser page. Later on, you can look into that.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And your main task will be working with little bit of images, audio files, just like last time you have done it with drop links, this time with unstructured.
PAUL: Sanjay, Kumar, please add the command in Notion. It's already there in requirement.txt. Please look into that. I have just done the editing of that in my TXT file, so I think you can do it.
PAUL: I won't be using Azure, it's completely AWS, so the idea is that you should have AWS.
PAUL: Lakshmi, it totally changes, like, you have to pick up a weekday, and it totally depends upon you guys.
PAUL: Okay, because yes, probably in January I might take a few extra classes.
PAUL: Few additional topics which are out of the syllabus, it will be always in extra classes only.
PAUL: That's me.
PAUL: Okay, yes, no more teaching, so let's start with the doubts. Mitesh, I think you can go ahead, I've already unmuted you. Then coming to Digvijay, then coming to Sanali, then coming to Aqik.
PAUL: A kick is there. Others, please.
Mitesh Shah: Yep. So thanks, Paul. One thing that I'm a little surprised right now is, I have two different Git pulls that I did, one for simple language and one for document parser. In one particular sequel, and I'm not using any virtual environment, I'm using the main Python.
Mitesh Shah: For one part, it is working correctly, the whole pipeline, rack pipeline, but the other part, which is basically document positive today, for unstructured, it completely failed.
PAUL: Okay, show me, show me. Probably some type of issues are there. See, that's why today I did the installation in front of you, Molly. Because sometimes, even I don't know, because I might get stuck at installation. It might… it takes me, like, sometimes 15 to 20 minutes, depends upon the time.
Mitesh Shah: I hope I'm audible.
PAUL: How much math should it take beyond we should…
PAUL: Which would have expected. Really, see, Muddhasar, even when I do it in front of…
Sonali: what they're saying.
Sonali: True.
PAUL: Okay, like, I… Please, who is this?
PAUL: So, Nali, please be on mute here.
PAUL: So, like, I even do face these issues, because exactly I don't know, like, compatibility issues can be there, because this is one major problem with respect to Python, very specifically. In other programming languages, we don't face such type of compatibility issues.
PAUL: Okay, like, one package to another. This is very specific to Python, so really you need to check. So I always suggest don't use the latest version, always try to go one or two versions below. That will be the strategy.
PAUL: Okay, so it's common, it's even for me. That's why, generally, in production, I always use something 3 months old, 4 months old. I always feel that it is better and stable, because at least for new releases.
PAUL: Okay, there will be a lot of bugs, second GitHub issues will come, you need to solve that, you really need to wait for the latest version of it. So always, focus at least 2-3 versions older.
PAUL: I'll let Matesh, start sharing.
PAUL: I think Matesh, please start sharing.
PAUL: Should I downgrade to 3.13.9? 3.13.9, Akhil, Babu… so what is the current version? 3.13.9 you can use. No issues. 3. But don't use 3.14. In 3.14, there can be a lot of problems.
PAUL: What is the first error that is coming?
Mitesh Shah: It is coming with respect to Langchen Olama.
Mitesh Shah: Yeah, so, if… even if I remove Langchen or Lama, if I… let me do that.
PAUL: Comment that line, okay, and try.
Mitesh Shah: It worked. Certainly, it started working, but for Ulama, it is not working then.
PAUL: See, so probably, like, check your Ollama services on Duva and Ulama, sir, based on.
Mitesh Shah: It's working, I'm pretty sure about it.
Mitesh Shah: It's working.
PAUL: Just type Ulama space tariff.
PAUL: If it is already serving… Okay, alright, already listening to put, fine. Now go back.
PAUL: Okay, now check the version of, Langchen Olama.
Mitesh Shah: Sadi, mama.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Do what… You don't use virtual environments.
Mitesh Shah: I used to, but something happened this week in my office, and…
Mitesh Shah: I had to reinstall the complete Python.
PAUL: Okay, Langchen below, it was their LL, I think, somewhere.
PAUL: Okay, Langchen Olama, okay? This is the version 1.00, okay? Check in PYPI. What is the version of Langchen Olama recently?
PAUL: Because this is the way only to debug. There is no other fixed one-shot solution that I can say, that in one-shot you can do it.
Mitesh Shah: 1961.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: No, no, this is the ulama. You have to look for lanchen ulama, no?
Mitesh Shah: Oh, Sonny, bye-bye.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the latest version, which is released in October 17.
PAUL: Okay? Now, go back, just open the Python shell, and just try to write that import. Let me see that, okay, from, shell it is working or not. Just write Python, hit enter.
PAUL: And copy-paste that line from Lanchen Olama.
PAUL: Because nothing. Because if it is not working, you have to uninstall this package again, do a reinstallation.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no. You have to open the Python shell.
PAUL: Okay, now some things with respect to your lanchan Core is uninstalled.
PAUL: Okay, a lot of things… that's why virtual environments are better, if you use it.
PAUL: We can do fun stuff.
PAUL: do… just open Python and hit enter. Write Python and hit enter.
PAUL: Copy that input from Langchen Ulama. Here only you are getting some error.
PAUL: This is a Pythonic error.
PAUL: Because your Python shell in the first step, only you got an attribute error. Nothing to do with you, I think so I have to…
Mitesh Shah: Because of the current error and this week I had it, this is… this is happening. I will reinstall complete stuff.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Please try it and then let me know.
Mitesh Shah: I will do that. Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, invitation… next… I think Sonali, you can go ahead. Dig Vijay, you can go ahead.
Digvijay: Yeah, highball.
PAUL: Yes.
Digvijay: How do we submit the assignment? Should we mail it to you?
PAUL: Drop me a yes, drop me a mail. Keep it in GitHub, that's the idea.
Digvijay: Okay, like, what is.
PAUL: Always share your… APP at the red krishnak.in. It's in the Notion also that you can check.
Digvijay: Okay, abp.krishna. Okay, that's it, yeah. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright, next, Sonali.
Sonali: Hi, Paul, how do I share my screen?
PAUL: Just wait, I will add you to panel list, then,
PAUL: Our kicker's done, I think, and Naga, you are there. Next.
PAUL: Yes, Madam.
Sonali: Wow.
Naga: Yeah, so I'm also having the… one of the installation errors.
PAUL: Alright, I will add you to panelist, okay, please check, okay? Harim, please go ahead. Akig?
PAUL: I think you already told, but your hand was raised, so I unmuted you. Hari, please go.
Hari Kumar: Minor insulation issue.
PAUL: Man, you were pro-man where you got stuck.
Hari Kumar: I'm getting sometimes.
Hari Kumar: aren't necessarily…
PAUL: It hap- it happens, I know.
PAUL: Because I know there are a few from older batches, okay, they are pretty much pros, guys.
PAUL: Promote to panelists, okay, I've done it for Hari, okay.
Sonali: Oh, S…
PAUL: Yes, tell me.
Sonali: Yeah, so I've tried to install, 0.86, 0.85, like, earlier. I checked these versions, and tried to install the older versions as well, from 882878685, but
Sonali: What are you exactly using? Because I'm still getting, error for…
PAUL: I didn't change, cloud services. Very specifically, I was working only on
PAUL: that Llama index and Llama index score. Only two packets that I have changed. Even in my system, okay, if I do a pip list.
PAUL: Just wait. I will be sharing my screen now, okay? Alright, now from here… okay. So, if you look into, I have never worked on that cloud service package. I have very specifically changed the package of Llama Index and Llama Index Code.
Sonali: VIN is not visible.
PAUL: I'm sharing my screen.
Sonali: Sorry, your screen is not visible.
PAUL: My screen, I think I've died.
Sonali: Only name, but not your…
PAUL: Please let me know, I think.
Naga: No, it is visible.
Naga: It is visible, it's fine.
PAUL: Please check, okay, because I know it is visible. I'm showing you that…
Naga: Go to the webinar, I think. She's seeing her own screen, that's a problem. She has to go to the webinar.
PAUL: Please change your screen. Okay, so only these two packages in my system that I have changed.
Sonali: No, I mean, I'm sharing my screen.
PAUL: He'll stop sharing. Okay, he'll stop sharing. If you stop sharing, then I think at least you can look into my screen.
Sonali: Yeah.
PAUL: complete.
Sonali: Yeah, I stopped sharing. Let me just take a screenshot of your versions.
PAUL: I have picked up… the recent version is 0.14.10.
Sonali: Dodge.
Sonali: 30 seconds.
PAUL: I'm just sharing it in the chat, also, so that for your.
Sonali: Llama index and Llama Index Code.
PAUL: Yes. These two are the main packages which was creating the issue. Llama Cloud Services actually didn't create that particular issue for me.
PAUL: So, very specifically, the package which creates the issue, you need to focus on that package only.
PAUL: In your error, very specifically, it was the Llama Index. So that's why you need to just take care of those two packages.
PAUL: Okay, now you share your screen.
Sonali: So, in my case, the exact error is on the Llama cloud services, not on the Llama index code.
PAUL: Fine. That Llama Cloud Services will get you to Llama Index only. Both the, imports take you to the same part. Start sharing. Okay, now see…
PAUL: Here, very specifically, cloud services, it is coming. Scroll down a little bit.
PAUL: After CloudServices.service.utels, import source text and file input.
PAUL: Okay, this is… okay, your one is coming from Llama Cloud Services, okay? Alright, right now, the recent version, you are using 0.6.85.
PAUL: Okay? Now, I will just do a pip list from my case, exactly which version that I'm using.
PAUL: My Llama Cloud version is… 0.6.54 that I am using.
PAUL: You can check with that particular version.
PAUL: 0.6.54.
PAUL: 6.54 at the last.
PAUL: Remove Utils, remove utilities? Yeah, only the name of the package.
Sonali: Firstly, uninstall.
PAUL: Okay, and then just make it 5-4. Remove 8-5.
PAUL: And change it to 5.4.
PAUL: Okay, now open the Python shell and copy-paste that, line from, directly. That is the fastest way, rather than executing it in your notebook.
Sonali: So, you've seen… Don't rent from here.
PAUL: Open the Python shell. Please write Python in your terminal and hit enter and copy-paste that link.
PAUL: Otherwise, I have to look into the other packages also.
Sonali: I'll definitely check that.
PAUL: Because this error is coming from cloud services only.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no. Just write Python in your terminal and hit enter.
PAUL: Close this one. You don't need… the VS Code terminal, yes, right here, Python, yes. Now, cov, you are also having a attribute backend error. This should not happen, there is some issue.
PAUL: with your core Python only.
PAUL: Whenever somebody opens a Python shell, there should not be any type of attribute error.
PAUL: PIP freeze, I can do a peep freeze, but my peep freeze won't work in your system, that's why.
PAUL: Okay, so…
Sonali: But when I opened the Python shell like this, there was no error here.
PAUL: But actually, you are using this Python environment. No, you are not using that Python environment. That is different, this is different.
PAUL: Because there is some issue with your Python, this attribute error readline has no attribute backend, because really you need to solve this issue, why this is coming, very specifically.
PAUL: Because the same issue was there with materials.
PAUL: Because this is some type of core Python issue that you need to resolve first.
PAUL: Then you have to look into the other part.
PAUL: Hagia, you can start sharing your screen, or Hari, anyone can comment.
PAUL: Very rarely. So, just check. The idea is that try to create a new environment, try to do the setup, that's the only way. The first thing, your Python should be working fine. If there is some issue with the Python, there can be some issues with respect to other packages also.
PAUL: Alright, Hari, I think you can start sharing. Hari.
PAUL: Hari Naga…
Hari Kumar: Here, I'm sharing my screen.
PAUL: Sonali, so try by creating a new environment, and just try to install only those Llama packages. Leave the unstructured, leave docklinks just focused on the packages which is used by Llama parts. Okay? Just create an isolated environment and check.
Sonali: Okay, okay, sure.
Sonali: Sure.
PAUL: Alright. I'm getting this Pondas error.
PAUL: Error, OS error… Process cannot access the file because it is used by another process.
PAUL: See, technical… Permission error, this is. Permission error is coming… permission error, how it comes… Like,
PAUL: Hmm…
PAUL: OS error could not install the package due to an OS error. Can you do it? Okay, leave it here.
PAUL: Okay, do it from the terminal, really, like…
PAUL: Here it happens, try to open the terminal.
Hari Kumar: Yeah, also, I saw that same error, like.
PAUL: Close your part shell, open your CMD, please.
PAUL: Opening your CMD?
PAUL: Open your CMD, first of all.
PAUL: This is, again, partial you have opened. Please open your CMT.
PAUL: From here, their drop-down is there, no, below the plus sign.
PAUL: Yes, from that drop-down. Below that, below that, from here, select command prompt, please.
PAUL: Command prompt. Command prompt.
PAUL: Yes. Okay? Alright. Now, your environment is my ENV, okay?
Hari Kumar: is…
PAUL: Alright. Now, you have already done the installation of the packages, or you are doing it? So, you can directly copy-paste that pip install.
Hari Kumar: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, and paste it there in the terminal. Let's say in the terminal what you are getting. Are you getting this?
PAUL: 1.
Hari Kumar: Shall I enter? Yeah.
PAUL: Aha, enter, enter.
PAUL: Whatever error will come now, only it will come.
PAUL: Most of the things are already satisfied. Now, see, here you didn't got the error.
Hari Kumar: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why most of the times you will see that I don't do it from Jupyter Notebook. Sometimes, some type of issue that comes around.
PAUL: Okay, so…
Hari Kumar: This is working, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, yes, because from the terminal, we did the check, and it is working.
Hari Kumar: Yes, yes, it's working, yes.
PAUL: So, that's the main thing. That's why I don't use directly from Jupyter Notebooks. I feel it's much safer from terminal. Jupyter Notebooks are your main application, which is the VS Code. There can be some permission issues. Because of that, it might…
PAUL: Get stuck during an execution.
Hari Kumar: Okay, okay, got it, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, Hari, all right, fine. Next, Naga, please start sharing your screen.
Naga: Yeah, just saying, you know what I'm saying?
Naga: So… I'm doing this…
Naga: So, install… I did the installation, so pip install this one. It came with some error, but it says…
Sonali: That helps me.
PAUL: Whatever the issues that you are getting, I can see a lot of pandas written.
PAUL: Panda C5… Debuild… please do the installation from terminally. Really, like, okay. Please try to do it from…
PAUL: From terminal, just open your CMD, okay, command prompt, activate your environment, the environment that you were using. Within that, please do the installation.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Because here it's telling, and… What's the error is coming.
PAUL: Please don't expose your keys.
Naga: Oh, God.
PAUL: What you are searching.
Naga: I was… that launching the environment… I was doing from always from the Jupyter note. It's not possible from Jupyter?
PAUL: It is possible, try to open terminal from Jupyter.
Naga: That's the only other thing that you can do.
Naga: No.
Naga: kernel?
PAUL: No, no, no, just, run, no, no, no, go beside.
PAUL: tabs, I think, because terminal can be launched from Jupyter also. I rarely use it, but yes, it is possible setting.
Naga: the guns…
PAUL: terminal theme is there, so I think a terminal button will be there.
Naga: Sure.
PAUL: Anybody using terminal here? Because I know the terminal is there.
PAUL: Below, below, below check, at the bottom, at the bottom, there is generally an option to open the terminal.
PAUL: There is only temple… Click on the plus sign, plus sign, with respect to tab.
PAUL: Click on the new sign, yeah, click on plus.
Naga: New lunch or okay.
PAUL: There is a terminal, can you…
PAUL: Okay, this is also partial. Your default…
PAUL: Defaults shall, at least when you are working with deep learning, please make it CMD.
Naga: Mars shall always create an issue.
PAUL: All right now… Nothing now, because here, switching of that switch, we cannot.
Naga: Yeah, it came. Yeah, it came. CMD.
PAUL: Okay, fine, then try to go into that path.
PAUL: Wherever you… your environment is there, please activate it, okay, and then we will look into that.
PAUL: There is some Python issue then, very specific channel.
PAUL: You need to probably reinstall Python or something like that. You need to take an approach.
PAUL: Because for your new environment only, try to create the environment in another way, rather than using UV. Okay, you need to check. Somehow, your Python should be working fine. If there is some issue with Python, other issues you might face.
PAUL: Okay, two people have raised their hand.
PAUL: Ashish, Nayak, and Muthasar.
Mudassar Hakim: Hey, boss, should I share my screen?
PAUL: Okay, I will put you to panelists, just wait.
PAUL: Ashish?
Ashish Nayak: Yeah, can I share my screen?
PAUL: Alright, Ashish, I will add you to panelist.
PAUL: Okay, Rohit, and… I think… Ulari. So, a few people I have…
PAUL: Unmuted, so you guys can go ahead.
Mudassar Hakim: Can you see my screen, Paul?
PAUL: Yes, I can see.
Mudassar Hakim: So, when I'm running this code, right, it breaks for some reason here. I'm just trying to figure it out. I ran it manually also, the document is there, it parses also, but when this piece of code runs, I'm just doing a…
Mudassar Hakim: You know, pre-check, just running the cells, just making sure everything is working properly.
PAUL: Seriously, it's not necessary. In my case also, I have not verified the code. I was only working on the imports, so, like, I need to check that part.
PAUL: In list index out of range.
Mudassar Hakim: Yo.
PAUL: It is fine.
Mudassar Hakim: In my case also, then it will be there.
PAUL: Because I know done the verification.
Mudassar Hakim: Here is the interesting thing, right? I manually do it, correct? I take the same code here, right? Which is over here.
Mudassar Hakim: And, okay, it's not fast mode, maybe that is one reason.
Mudassar Hakim: Kicked.
Mudassar Hakim: So, I was just trying to figure out what is going on, because the documents are getting loaded, but…
PAUL: because based on the error that you have, it's an index one, so probably where that indexing we are doing for document 0, so there probably see loaded zero documents.
Mudassar Hakim: Interesting. This is interesting. So it's only happening for preset fast.
Mudassar Hakim: If I remove this preset password, right, it runs.
PAUL: Yes, I think, because the number of documents that are coming… now, in that case, the root came, because of that, the error was list indexed.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, but why a preset should break for parsing? I mean, okay, not a question for today, but, yeah, strange.
Mudassar Hakim: Because if I don't know Yes, sir.
PAUL: Little bit in the documentation, we have to go, and really we have to look into.
Mudassar Hakim: Baby.
PAUL: like, what is the main cause? Because other than that, I know that, yes, it is getting loaded, so because of 0 that is coming, that's why the list index becomes dire.
Mudassar Hakim: This is… really helps, Paul, you know, if I see the things before, and I at least run it, forget understanding, I will understand when the session comes. But if I run it in.
PAUL: Like, this week, even vectorized notebook that I'll be creating, that also I'll be uploading by Wednesday.
PAUL: Okay, you can look… take a new poll, probably at least one or two days before, because that content also… because I will be doing some rebank, but that will be the more or lesser same content.
Mudassar Hakim: Right, right, yeah, great, thanks.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Next.
Ashish Nayak: Share my screen? Yeah, I've already promoted to panelist.
PAUL: Madrid, start sharing, please start sharing. Ashish.
Ashish Nayak: So here I'm… I just…
Ashish Nayak: have all the latest versions, 0.14.8, and the Lama cloud service is also 0.6.54, but when I'm running this…
Ashish Nayak: import statement, it just gives me this error, cannot import…
PAUL: This is the same error that I was getting in class.
PAUL: If you remember. Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now.
Ashish Nayak: one of this.
PAUL: what I did. First of all, just check the version that you are using. Do a pip list, and show me the current versions.
Ashish Nayak: Just to…
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, I cut it.
Ashish Nayak: So I already did the paper list.
Ashish Nayak: So this is the…
PAUL: Lama index version that you are using is 14.8. Okay, and the Lama index score that you are using?
PAUL: is also 14.8. Cloud services also you are using, 0.6.54.
PAUL: Okay, now this looks good to me, because most of the packages are synced based on my
PAUL: one Lama Parse version, just scroll below what is the version of Llama Parse that you were using.
PAUL: So I'm using 0.6.54, yes. All the version matches with me, exactly the one that I'm working with.
Ashish Nayak: Yep.
PAUL: Okay, now.
Ashish Nayak: Can you suggest what your, LLM OpenAI version is?
PAUL: I'm hoping…
Ashish Nayak: this LLM.
PAUL: Llama… no, no, no, this Llama Index Embeddings OpenAI is 0.5.1.
PAUL: I don't think this package will create an issue, because really, right now, we are not…
PAUL: really looking into that. So your version is, 0.5.1, I think.
PAUL: For OpenAI.
PAUL: I am using 0.5.1.
PAUL: Please have.
Ashish Nayak: Select changes.
PAUL: Because right now, ASC, right now the issue is coming from two packages.
PAUL: The Lama Index and the Lama Index code. These two things, probably, you can do a downgrade. What is the Python version?
Ashish Nayak: My Python version, just one.
PAUL: This is the version of UV we'll be getting, no?
PAUL: You have to write Python, hit enter, you will get it.
PAUL: Python FN, FN version, you can do a Python or a tenth.
PAUL: If you're using something, okay, again, in your case, the same issue.
PAUL: This backend issue is coming wide to so many people? Three people right now, all sharing the screen.
Rohit Srivastava: Sarang Shu, the challenge what I was looking for is, look, it appears that Python 3.13 is not compatible with Lama parsers.
PAUL: I am using… I am using which version? Others are also using 3.13.
Rohit Srivastava: I know too long.
PAUL: 14 is not compatible, but at least…
PAUL: Please let me know, people who are using, 3-rotop, because I know others are using that swipe.
Rohit Srivastava: And I'm facing serious issues with this, and this is where I would need your help. Thank you.
PAUL: Mmm… just wait, let me see once, okay?
Rohit Srivastava: Peace.
PAUL: Because, see, my Python version is 3.13.9.
Sonali: Alright.
Rohit Srivastava: My default is 3.13.1. 3.13.1, yeah.
PAUL: So I don't think there will be any issues with respect to Python version 30, really.
PAUL: Like, I'm doing it, others are in… Amit is telling he's on 3.13.7, so really, I don't think 3.13 will.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright.
PAUL: Any issue with respect to life?
Rohit Srivastava: So let's see. Let's create an environment right from the zero.
PAUL: Okay.
Ashish Nayak: So what's with the version 3.13?
PAUL: Anything, like 3.13 you can use, even 3.12.9 also you can use.
PAUL: But don't pick up something from 3.14. The idea is stick to 3.13 only.
Ashish Nayak: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so try that, because with respect to dependency issues, that's the only thing.
Rohit Srivastava: Yes.
PAUL: Don't do an exit from here. Ashish, I think you are sharing your screen. Please first do an exit.
PAUL: Now… What is the Python version it was showing there?
Ashish Nayak: $3.13.
PAUL: If I… the version here is there is no issue with the version, I know it will work fine. Okay, now, just do one thing, just uninstall two packages, if you remember. The Llama Index and the Llama Index Core, and downgrade them to some below versions.
Sonali: So, probably, you can pick up.
PAUL: paper…
PAUL: Wherever you have taken that.
PAUL: Mmm, alright, that's the thing. For somebody, it works, and for somebody…
Ashish Nayak: So I just need to fix, llama Index.
PAUL: Yes, because you're… yes, try to downgrade both of them. Just try to.
Ashish Nayak: open.
PAUL: Because that's the only thing, because in your case, both are there. First, uninstall, and do a fresh installation of those two packages.
PAUL: And use some more versions around, because your version and my versions are exactly the same.
PAUL: So probably you can do a downgrade, probably you can pick up something like 0.14.6 or 7.
PAUL: Because right now, I think you are using 0.14.8.
PAUL: So just try to downgrade from your existing one.
Ashish Nayak: Sure, we'll try. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Rohit, let me know your status.
PAUL: Yes… Okay, how does, like, whoever is there in that Indies, I have one muted, they can go ahead.
PAUL: this part, I know it's a little bit frustrating, but the idea is that just be calm, because
PAUL: That's the only solution. It might take some time, okay, and you can always refer to GitHub issues. That is the main, I feel that, better than ChatGPT at any point of time, or…
PAUL: claud anything. GitHub issues or something, like, recently solved, it might… Get some type of problem.
PAUL: I think in your case, you have to write script slash activate, no? In that way. Naga.
Naga: Hmm? Scripts slash activities.
PAUL: I think something like that, generally in Windows.
PAUL: That happens. You're in VAP.
Naga: scripts, right? Like, in this, parser, I don't have any script like this, this is docking like this.
PAUL: So, which environment you were using?
Naga: I was directly using the Jupyter shell, and from here, see, like, I'll show you, this is my administration. So, this is the other one.
PAUL: So this is a Jupyter shell from here.
Naga: It is using…
PAUL: Yeah, it's… cannot create directive slash dot ENUV and other stuff. See, the idea is…
PAUL: you create a virtual environment. Within that virtual environment, you always install the package, pip install Jupyter. You do that.
Rohit Srivastava: I'm just gonna do the name.
Naga: So…
Rohit Srivastava: Actually, Blackwall Alina charitable businesses me up.
PAUL: Okay, so see, that is the idea, always create an environment within that, install Jupyter.
Naga: So…
PAUL: So…
PAUL: Because, see, whenever you are directly opening Jupyter, it means that the default interpreter which is there in your system, it is getting invoked.
PAUL: And really, like, a lot of packages that you might have installed previously, there can be a lot of conflicts.
PAUL: the idea of creating a separate BNB. What you can do? Just create a new virtual environment, do the installation, and check right now.
PAUL: That is the cleanest way that even I do it. Delete it, okay, create a new environment, activate it, install the packages, check now.
PAUL: All right, to the call.
Sonali: Can I share my screen?
PAUL: Yes, please go ahead, Sonali.
PAUL: So, simply, create an environment, first of all.
Sonali: I have resolved that, Python shell issue.
PAUL: Alright.
Sonali: Okay, so if I now open the Python shed here, it is working fine, right?
PAUL: Mmm.
Sonali: what you were saying, right?
PAUL: Yes, this part is fine, no issues.
Sonali: So, yeah.
PAUL: You have given the name of the environment llama-.
Sonali: Yeah, but then…
PAUL: It's December, okay.
Sonali: 6th December.
PAUL: Okay, frame, print, friend.
PAUL: Okay, now, here's just try to copy-paste that…
Sonali: I am still having issue with cloud service.
PAUL: Okay, fine. This is not an issue, this is the… you have to resolve this one.
PAUL: See, this is simply, like, a package dependency or a compatibility issue. Now, this, every developer needs to work on this one. Just try to hit enter here. The same error, if you get, it means that there is some issue with the package. Hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, it's taking time, alright, fine, let's wait.
Sonali: Hi, dear.
PAUL: Okay, fine, fine, let's wait. Okay, now see, here it is working.
PAUL: So, how it is working here?
Sonali: Yes.
PAUL: Because the environment that you are using is…
Sonali: Subsequently.
PAUL: We were using… see, the environment I can see there, it's ENV5 December, on top, the kernel.
PAUL: Please check exactly which kernel you are using.
Sonali: Cody.
PAUL: Python environments, click it. If you have your existing.
Sonali: My bank.
PAUL: Let me install, install it, yes. Generally, the idea is, whenever you are working, do a pip, install Jupyter.
Sonali: Oh.
PAUL: That's why I always say do the verification from terminal for everyone.
PAUL: Because going forward, like, I will be using Jupyter Notebooks, but if I switch to scripts, really, like.
PAUL: Scripts gives you a better idea working with.
PAUL: There is some red mark that is going below your taskbar check, what is that error that is coming around?
PAUL: in your task personality, I think some red-red.
PAUL: Just check whether there is a pop-up or something like this.
PAUL: Okay, this is your… no, no, no, the other one looks like it's gone.
PAUL: Okay, I think the candlel is activated.
Sonali: Yeah, just introduce…
PAUL: Okay, okay. Try to, restart the cell, restart the kernel, and try to re-execute once.
Sonali: Maybe I have to, explicitly install IPyKernel here, otherwise it doesn't work.
PAUL: Okay.
Sonali: Because this will be… Stop.
PAUL: Generally, when I install the package Jupyter, everything comes pre-installed with that.
PAUL: Fine, just try to do a restart once we have done that.
Sonali: This is fine.
Sonali: Yep, thank you.
Sonali: Dwarf.
PAUL: It was working.
PAUL: After creating the new environment. Alright, fine. So now, let's move to our next…
Kodali Purna Chand: Paul, can you make me a presenter?
Naga: So I have…
PAUL: fortunate.
PAUL: Roeth, let me know your status here.
Naga: So I have…
PAUL: I can iPhone, all right.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, Paul, hey, Sarangqu, I'm here. You want me to share my screen?
PAUL: Let me know the status, like, you are trying from creating.
Rohit Srivastava: No, I was trying, but still, I've given it up.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, I will add you to panelist, okay? Please, thank you.
Naga: So this one, I created one environment, okay, but how do I get into this environment, activate… Oof.
PAUL: Like, for Windows, the scripts, really, I'm not used to, but I think it is some scripts slash activate, like, name of the environment in that beta.
Naga: Yeah, scripts last activate, but see, like, if I activate this, there is no scripts in the… this one, right?
PAUL: So, where you have created the virtual environment, what is the command that you have used?
Naga: This is a command, okay, the Python…
PAUL: This is not a command.
PAUL: This is not a command to create a virtual environment.
Naga: Virtual… virtual environment.
PAUL: See, working with virtual environment, focus on that thing later on.
Naga: Conda… Conda was the one we originally started, right? So, the virtual environment, but we… I don't want to use Conda.
Naga: Instead, I…
PAUL: Whichever way you do it, the idea is that you should be very good with creating environments and deleting environments, again, creating, installing. This stuff has to be… be in your mind, rather than learning this, because this is the first step, always.
PAUL: So, commands are very important, and these type of commands you need. Like, see, myenv slash privbs.activate.
PAUL: This is the actual command for Windows.
PAUL: to activate it, first of all, you have to create the environment. Like, for example, if you want to use Python, then python-M, VNV now, that is the command. Then the name of the environment will be myENV.
Naga: So that is what I've done here. See, Python, minus M, iTunnel in.
PAUL: That is a different command. I'm telling you. It's a different command.
PAUL: For creating environments, the command is always small.
PAUL: Excellent.
PAUL: Go into the project directory, then create. Now, why you are creating inside System.tool?
Naga: Oh, go ahead,
Naga: So it's…
PAUL: These are common practices. The idea is that where is your project directory, you should be there.
Naga: Yeah, this is the collective tool now.
PAUL: Okay, I'm looking into now, because the Ali, okay, Purnachan, sir, screen. Okay, sir, please tell me, like, where you were stuck.
PAUL: This is telling export to dict from dockling. I think this is a dockling error that you are getting.
PAUL: Export to date, okay, fine.
PAUL: Attribute error, mock document object as now, export to dict. Okay, alright, let me just do a search for talk links, export to dict, because I know this function is there. Export to dict.
PAUL: Export to touch… talk a link.
Naga: Oops.
PAUL: Yes, export to dict is there…
PAUL: Alright, now… please, let me know your docklink version.
PAUL: What is the Doppling version you are using? Please let me know.
PAUL: Okay, just do a pip show.link there, yes.
PAUL: Because in the official documentation, it is mentioned.
PAUL: If selling the docklink package is only not there, you need to install Docklink.
Naga: Excuse me.
PAUL: Please do the installation of Docklink.
PAUL: Paper install docklink, you have to do it.
PAUL: Please check that, okay, and then let me know once you have done the installation.
PAUL: Okay, UVPIP show… no, no, no, CCC. UV… are you using UV? Because once you have written the command without UV, if you're using UV, then do UV pipipshow.l link.
PAUL: If you are always using UV.
Naga: If so… button.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: not found. You need to install the package. Docklink is missing. Please do the installation and then try.
Naga: So far, I went into the… this, into my environment, okay? .
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: And then.
PAUL: Go… come out of scripts, you don't need to be inside the scripts folder.
Naga: You have to be inside that main folder.
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: Yeah, I'm in the main folder, no?
PAUL: one more, one… okay, yes, fine. Okay, now, here, try to, do that. So, whenever you are working here, first of all, try to install the Jupyter. Pay, pencil Jupyter, try it here.
Naga: Already Jupyter is there, but can I not use the…
PAUL: That is a different Jupyter, it is at global interpreter level. That is not in your environment level.
Naga: Understand.
Naga: Okay, myself, Edward.
Naga: I'm struggling.
Naga: decided they're not open.
PAUL: Upgrading is not required. I quickly install PIP install generator.
Naga: or JupyterLab, you can do it.
Naga: Lists.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: That will take time.
Naga: So I will close the existing Jupyter notebook.
PAUL: Please be good at creating environments in Christmas.
PAUL: If you are stuck at this point.
PAUL: It becomes really a problem to debugging. Later on, more packages will come when we discuss projects.
PAUL: Okay, now install the packages with respect to, whichever thing that, like, llama part, that part you were trying.
Naga: Yeah, requirements, right? Requirements, right?
PAUL: From requirements, very specifically, just pick up those related to llamas.
Naga: Okay, just fill on us.
Naga: They've been installed.
Naga: Let's see if this leads to…
PAUL: Yes, all these packages related to Llama, copy-paste it, or bring it in a single line. You have to keep all those by your space.
Naga: And then 15… okay.
PAUL: Huh, paper installed directly the package.
Naga: Welcome.
Naga: Slash, slashing bit…
Naga: Okay, single line, and paper pencil.
PAUL: Yes, copyright before that, write paper install.
PAUL: Okay? Copy-paste it, and paste it in that terminal.
Naga: Nope.
PAUL: Late enter.
Naga: Yep.
PAUL: Wait, it will take time to do the installation.
Naga: of…
PAUL: Now, open your Python shell, okay, and go back to that notebook. In the import section, there was a piece of line which was written. Just try to import it.
PAUL: from Lama Parse or Llama Cloud Services input to that particular line, we can do the testing.
PAUL: Open the notebook.
Naga: Notebook is this one.
PAUL: Open with a… yes, anyone. Okay? Yes, scroll down.
PAUL: Scroll down, scroll below. Below, below, below, below, below, below, below. Okay, yes, and the import section, go below.
PAUL: Go below, go below, go below. Yes, now this is the part, okay? Now, from here, line number 150.
PAUL: Okay, from that part copy, line number 150, from, from llama Parse copy, that thing. Not that entire line, only from llama underscore parse, input lama parse, that line.
Naga: Okay, good, okay.
PAUL: Okay, and once the installation is done in the terminal, open your Python shell and try to execute the command.
Naga: This one, okay.
Naga: So there's installation still going on.
PAUL: Yes, it will take some time.
PAUL: Ruth, you can share your screen in the meantime.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, there we go.
Rohit Srivastava: Right.
Rohit Srivastava: You can see my screen.
PAUL: Yes, I can.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, thank you. So, so there is…
Rohit Srivastava: I mean, I don't know, I mean, looks like I'm… I'm really struggling with the versions of.
PAUL: Persion issue, every Python developer. It's not software, it's a one-time thing, so one.
Rohit Srivastava: I know, I know, I know, I know.
PAUL: That's, like, one-time task for Indiana.
Rohit Srivastava: directory files, sample documents, that's…
PAUL: See, here, path is not defined. Like, I think in the top, there will be an import very specific.
Rohit Srivastava: No, the… huh? Oh, yeah.
PAUL: And Mr.
Rohit Srivastava: This is where the… this is where I'm getting errors.
Rohit Srivastava: Just a minute.
Naga: Paul, this is in Stern, so I.
PAUL: Okay, go below, go below, go below the last line, tell me, like, what is the error. From Llama Cloud Services, it went to Llama's same chat message. You need to, downgrade. This is the same error even I was getting.
Rohit Srivastava: So how did you resolve it?
PAUL: I just thought in front of you only. Open your terminal, just do a clear, right clear, and remove everything.
PAUL: There we go. Alright. Now, the first thing, are you using UV? Then do an UV pip list.
PAUL: Okay, now check the version of Lama Index and LAMAI index score.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, just a minute.
Rohit Srivastava: Lama Index, and now my index code. These are the two versions.
PAUL: Okay, Llama index is 0.9.48, this is a very old version of Llama Index that you need to uninstall.
PAUL: And LamaIntex score, I think, 0.14.8 that I was using. Okay, so first of all, uninstall Lama Index, and install the version of Lama Index, 0.14.8.
Rohit Srivastava: You… just a minute, give me one minute.
PAUL: UV, paperless.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, yeah, paper, uninstall.
PAUL: Bama.
Rohit Srivastava: my mom.
PAUL: L-A-M-A hyphen index.
Rohit Srivastava: Index…
PAUL: Enter.
Rohit Srivastava: Lame… Lama?
Rohit Srivastava: Cool, right?
PAUL: Hyphen index hyphen core.
PAUL: LAMAI index hyphen core it was.
Rohit Srivastava: Llama index hyphen core, okay, okay, okay, just a minute.
PAUL: Okay.
Rohit Srivastava: hyphen code. Okay, great. No worries.
PAUL: Alright, fine, okay? Now, just, press the arrow key, and do a UV pip install. Remove that on part.
PAUL: And in both the places, we'll be adding the versions. So, llama hyphen index is equal to, is equal to 2 times equal to. After that, pass 0.14.8.
Rohit Srivastava: $14.
PAUL: 0.14.8, right, 0 also.
PAUL: Okay, and similarly for, llama, index core, right? llama hyphen index hyphen core.
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, oh, wait a minute, wait a minute. Lama…
Rohit Srivastava: Index and LAMAI index score, okay. Index.
PAUL: Index, hyphen core, same version, 0.14.8.
Rohit Srivastava: 0 dot… 14.8.
Rohit Srivastava: All right, yeah. No, it's saying, oops, oops, oops, my phone back, bad.
Rohit Srivastava: We'll have to restart the kernel.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no. Before restarting, just copy-paste that line where it was failing, from llama underscore cloud services, input lama parse, copy-paste, copy that line.
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, okay.
PAUL: in that.
Rohit Srivastava: typing in Python, okay. Yeah, got it.
PAUL: Always check through the pipeline.
Rohit Srivastava: industry.
PAUL: it's better.
Rohit Srivastava: Nice to hear.
PAUL: First, I made.
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, it did. It did.
PAUL: do?
Rohit Srivastava: It did. Yeah, it did. Thank you so much.
Rohit Srivastava: Look, the bike…
PAUL: outright, too.
Rohit Srivastava: I knew I was struggling with versioning only, but thanks.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Yes, please let me know.
Naga: Paul?
Naga: all this, installation was completed, okay? It told it completely… Wait, wait, wait.
PAUL: with… with…
PAUL: installation was completed fine. After that, I asked you, write Python and hit enter, and then pass that import.
PAUL: Glad have you.
PAUL: Hit enter.
PAUL: Yes, hit enter, done. Okay, now…
Naga: No, put this.
PAUL: Yeah, okay.
PAUL: Okay, now pass that from Lama Power to input Llama barge. Okay, yeah.
Naga: Oh, no.
PAUL: None.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now hit enter, see if you are getting any error or not. If you are not getting any error, this is a warning, this is fine.
Naga: Jump.
PAUL: Okay, it is working. Okay.
Naga: Hmm.
PAUL: And as this is a common thing, now go back to your terminal, do an right here exit.
PAUL: Bracket, open, bracket, close, first bracket.
Naga: That's wonderful.
PAUL: Ctrl-Z also you can do. Now, see, whenever, for this environment, you want to open the Jupyter notebook, right? Jupyter-Notebook.
Naga: Yes, yes.
PAUL: Always. Then… Write hyphen, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, in a single, no space.
PAUL: It means that you are activating the Jupyter from your virtual environment. Without space, it…
PAUL: I activate the global one.
Naga: Understood. Oh, okay.
Naga: Unless we're honest.
PAUL: Nothing wrong.
PAUL: Alright, then, I will, which is also done, switching back to attendees, Amit… yes, Amit.
Amit Singh: Paul, sir, thank you so much, seeing other people resolve… I was able to resolve the LamaPars error. I didn't get that. So, moving ahead in 2.1, I'm getting a validation error, understanding the…
Amit Singh: Llama parts architecture.
Amit Singh: Possibly.
PAUL: Show me, because really, I've not tested that entire Llama parts document till now.
PAUL: I've created the content, but I need to test it out once, but soon.
Amit Singh: Oh yeah, I'll just share my screen.
PAUL: Yes.
Amit Singh: Yeah, this one.
Amit Singh: So, this ran fine, I mean, the above things have ran fine.
PAUL: No, no, this is nothing related to Lava Pass, it was just downloading one. Here, what is the issue that you are getting?
Amit Singh: Validation errors.
PAUL: Go back, go back. Value your API key is required.
Amit Singh: So that I have passed… that I have passed.
PAUL: Where is that .env file?
Amit Singh: That's what I… I… it is here.
PAUL: It is here, but in your project structure, I can.
Amit Singh: It is smart.
PAUL: anywhere.
Amit Singh: Fair enough.
Amit Singh: Okay, just… okay, it's in… There is one man.
PAUL: Alright, I got your problem. Aapne ye .env banatiya sample underscore documents dandar. Jesske karen…
PAUL: it could not look into it. The idea is that it should be always in your root directory.
PAUL: dot env file jo hot hai.
Amit Singh: directory, so I create in document parts rag main, right?
PAUL: created inside sample documents. Like, sample documents can undergo technical.
Amit Singh: Right, right, okay.
PAUL: to be there in the root directory. A problem, or Gujni.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay, okay, got your point. So, what do I do? Then I create, like.
PAUL: root directory, that's the only thing that you need to do. Drag karke, just pull karke, just bring it to the root directory.
PAUL: Nothing you have to do, you just pull that file.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay.
PAUL: drag, karke.
Amit Singh: Oh, girl.
PAUL: Basically, you need to bring it that, yes.
PAUL: Or do it from File Explorer, whichever works for you. Yes.
PAUL: Yay, sample 1 cup mug, I think. Because of that, it's telling sample 1.
PAUL: And we go move Kiji out.
Amit Singh: Probably with my mouse, actually. I mean, the…
PAUL: Generally, you see, like,
PAUL: when you are doing the setup, so the CP command is there, you can use it directly.
Amit Singh: Oh, got your point, okay, done.
PAUL: Okay, now try. Restart the kernel. Restart the kernel, restart.
Amit Singh: Lid.
PAUL: Because, Joe, I think in the first cell only, there was very specifically the detection for Lama Parsity. So that cell, there it will print you, this is the key.
Amit Singh: This is getting hidden behind this…
Amit Singh: What would it be installed, yeah.
Amit Singh: Okay, first cell you mean to say, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
PAUL: Niche, ha. Yaha pekin aapka ki jo haiken, it should detect. So, load it, ig bar, kar dije load.
Amit Singh: Okay, now diki, os.environment, llama Cloud API gee, igua rilan kijay deki kamkarayan.
Amit Singh: Yes.
Amit Singh: Yes, yes, so…
PAUL: kara aka.
Amit Singh: Right.
Amit Singh: So it has to be defined in the very, yeah.
Amit Singh: Yes.
PAUL: So you're.
Amit Singh: Yeah, yeah, yeah, thanks, thank you.
PAUL: Alright.
Amit Singh: Great, Paul, sir. Thanks a ton.
PAUL: Alright, Ahmed…
PAUL: Please make me presenter. You are in the presenter. You can share your screen directly. Only you are there. Nobody else is here.
PAUL: You can start presenting.
PAUL: Please start presenting. You are in the panelist.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: There is no audio from my side.
PAUL: Naga is telling me, make me a presenter, okay? Naga, raise your hand, otherwise I have to search through the entire list.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Please let me know with audio, because I cannot hear it.
PAUL: I'm not getting any audio from your site.
PAUL: Okay, Naga, promote to panelist, I have added you.
PAUL: Yes, so exactly…
PAUL: what you are doing. I can see here, UBPIP show talking, there is no package, you need to install the package.
PAUL: UVPIP install docklink that you can do.
Naga: Llama Key Loadogan.
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: Here's a good one.
PAUL: Yes, this is working.
Naga: Would I agree?
Naga: And there you go. Silver.
PAUL: Yes, this is working.
Naga: It looks awesome.
Naga: Cool.
PAUL: Huh.
Naga: A little sample chemical.
PAUL: This is working, this is working.
Naga: You're telling me…
PAUL: also working.
Naga: Yeah.
PAUL: Fine, now, this is working. Next class, we'll be discussing about this. Everything is working fine now.
Naga: Okay. Yeah, thank you so much, Paul. I will, ensure that I will keep it ready like this.
PAUL: Okay, alrighty, I'll change the way.
PAUL: Yes, Mr. Podali, so I can see your screen, but exactly, like, okay, right now you have installed Dockling, I'm getting, I think, because of 2.51, okay, fine.
PAUL: Now, in the next step.
PAUL: You have to directly, okay, you are going down, okay, fine.
PAUL: Actually, directly before this, you need to export others also, like, the other cells need to be executed, it's not like…
PAUL: In one shot directly to… Step-by-step, this is… because where a doc is defined.
PAUL: Those things will come into the picture.
PAUL: Because in the official documentation, I saw that, export to date option is there. So I know that it should work.
PAUL: I'm checking from the input side once more or direct. Can I get anything like that?
PAUL: So this is really taking a lot of time.
PAUL: Okay, so… test it, because, that particular sense… see, the idea is that you can pass anything, okay?
PAUL: Let's… Okay, once this document processing is done.
PAUL: Then, probably, let me do it.
PAUL: I think the number of pages which are there…
PAUL: Yes, sir.
PAUL: Alright, fine, your audio is not working. But see, like, just scroll above, let me just tell you, because that export to date that you have.
PAUL: Where that functionally exactly comes.
PAUL: So, for example, you have done converter.convert, okay, and then…
PAUL: See, go back to any cell, it means that any cell where you're, right now, that PDF was loading, go back to that.
PAUL: Okay, so just check if the PDF is loaded or not.
PAUL: That cell that you were executing.
PAUL: Okay, it looks like 2.17 done. Okay, now I'm just telling you, see. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, here only, okay? Execute this cell. Doc difficult to result.document.
PAUL: Execute.
PAUL: Did it got executed? 0.00 seconds?
PAUL: Alright, fine, it got executed, okay? Now, create a new cell. Create a new cell here, below this one.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, the idea is, see, you have that dog variable. Go above, you have that very specific dog variable, so using that particular dog variable, you can actually do the export, this dog. So, just try, like, doc.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, now this variable, doc dot, then export to date. Try this one.
PAUL: underscore 2, underscore harm. You can see, automatically, it came in the prediction also. So I feel that it should be available. Try to execute this.
PAUL: Yes, this method is there. I know that.
PAUL: Now, it's not throwing any error.
PAUL: And try to add the brackets, sorry, please add the brackets after dict, bracket, open, bracket, close, like a function. Yes, now try to execute this one.
PAUL: The instance has been shown here. Can you see? Export to text is working.
PAUL: Because, right now, this is JSON serializable dict, so I know that that part is working. Now, you need to check very specifically why this part is not working.
PAUL: Okay, because the attribute is there that we have confirmed. Now you have to really check the document is getting loaded, and based on that, you can test it out. Okay?
PAUL: So, I just told you. So, at any point of time after loading the document, you can do a detect operation. So, yes, it is working.
PAUL: Alright, now, from your side, please do check, okay? Alright, now I think, guys, we are done, so next week, we will start with LamaPath, and then Vectorize, and provided, let's see, next week, we will start the project, probably the next after that.
PAUL: Okay, so everyone, thanks for joining. Okay, so today's… it was less content that we have discussed, but fine. Let's meet next week, and we will continue our discussion. Bye-bye, everyone, thanks for joining.
PAUL: And I will add the assignment. Please do look into the assignment and try to at least attempt.